<section>
	<title>RHSA-2014:1317 - Security, Bug Fix, and Enhancement Update</title>
		<variablelist>
			<title>Appliance</title>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1106331">1106331</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>If a user assigned to any role other then super_admin logged into a CFME instance which did not have a provider configured yet, he would get the generic error message "The system has not been configured, please contact the administrator". The error message has been updated to a more descriptive one - "Logins not allowed, no providers are being managed yet. Please contact the administrator."
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1034477">1034477</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Services sub-tabs could not be individually enabled. In order to view one sub-tab a user have to be granted full permissions for the Services tab. The feature check for the Services tab has been updated to enable permissions for individual sub-tabs.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1029654">1029654</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Cloud relationships were not properly exposed to automate service models, resulting in missing key pairs for EC2 instances. A code update fixes the cloud relationships and key pairs for EC2 instances now populate the service models correctly.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1086015">1086015</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Selecting a VM under the Infrastructure tab took anywhere from 10-18 seconds due to slow database queries. Improvements were made in the VM selection code in the appliance. It is now possible to select VMs under the infrastructure tab without a delay.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1045062">1045062</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Deploying multiple virtual machines failed with the following message:

"RhevmApiError: Failed updating the properties of the VM. This may be caused either by:
1. The values selected are not appropriate for the VM; or
2. Its values cannot be updated while the VM is in UP state (Please shut down the VM in order to modify properties such as CPU or cluster)."

This was caused by RHEV-M returning a state of "complete" in the creation_status URL, leading to a request being made to the RHEV API to change a value on the virtual machine, but the virtual machine's URL was still reporting a state of "image_locked". A test has been added to to detect and re-queue the modification request if the destination image is in a state of "image_locked". The virtual machines now deploy successfully.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1045210">1045210</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>A code error caused custom button groups not to appear when viewing a Service. A code fix enables custom buttons to display correctly for Service and specific Service Templates on the Service summary screen.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1098648">1098648</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>The CFME appliance has two swap utilization thresholds to protect the operation of the appliance, at 60% and 80%. A bug got intorduced in these thresholds when the worker management code was refactored to fix another bugzilla. While the 80% swap utilization threshold was recognized, neither the 60% nor the 80% thresholds were honored.
This bug was fixed by re-enabling the check for swap space when starting workers.
As a result of this fix, the swap utilization thresholds are now honored correctly.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1119453">1119453</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Previously, turning on replication on the Regional Database caused the backlog to grow indefinitely. As a consequence, replicating to Master database was unresponsive for a long period of time and timed out. With this update, the bug has been fixed and Regional Database replication now works as expected.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1050208">1050208</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Dependency issues caused problems when updating CloudForms Management Engine with multiple default repositories enabled. This fix adds a set of patches to better manage the subscription process and limit the updates to the CloudForms Management Engine repository. This fix also adds a field in the Red Hat Updates section to define the CloudForms Management Engine repository name.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1135050">1135050</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the beta version of CloudForms Management Engine 5.3, running the rake command to precompile assets failed with the error asset logical path has no extension, for a file named without an extension. This was because the precompiler could not work with a filename without an extension. The bug was resolved by excluding files without extensions from precompiling. Precompiling assets now works as expected.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1054901">1054901</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>When provisioning a large number of virtual machines with Red Hat Enterprise Virtualization 3.2, some machines were created but not powered on due to request timeout errors. Timeout support for RHEV-M API calls have been added to the CFME appliance. Virtual machines now power on successfully.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1004894">1004894</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>With a large number of events in the event queue, the delete event for hosts, clusters, or management systems timed out due to a dead lock. This meant that the user was unable to remove hosts, clusters, or management systems within the Cloud Forms Management Engine environment. Changes were made so that the purger component would handle all events. The user is now able to remove hosts, clusters, and management systems within the Cloud Forms Management Engine environment.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1058261">1058261</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Certain charts and dash board graphics were not displayed correctly in Internet Explorer 8 due to incorrect browser detection. The browser detection code was updated to ensure that Internet Explorer 8 was detected correctly. All graphics and charts are not displayed correctly in Internet Explorer 8.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1095407">1095407</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Automation that should be zone specific for a certain EMS was being picked up by other zones. This was causing automation to fail because the EMS severs in that zone do not have access to the vCenter.  Since a service request zone is always nil, VM provisions tasks can fail when running under a service request due to selecting the wrong zone.

Request tasks should use the zone of their source object not the request. Updated file vmdb/app/models/miq_request_task/state_machine.rb which has now fixed the issue and the automation does not fail.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1058915">1058915</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>When connecting to a virtual machine from CloudForms EVM using the latest version of VMRC, the process failed to complete, resulting in issues like the console button being rendered unusable, or error messages such as the VMRC plugin not being installed or that the feature is only available in Firefox or Internet Explorer. The two major issues were that EVM was using previously installed versions of VMRC rather than the most updated ones and that EVM, in some cases, was incorrectly detecting Internet Explorer 11 as Firefox and providing wrong paths. These issues have been fixed in the most recent version. Connecting to a virtual machine from CloudForms EVM should work correctly.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1121202">1121202</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>The vmdb/public/assets directory did not exist on product appliance builds during development stages of CFME 5.3.0. The build process was changed to precompile the assets and make them available as a part of the source tarball used to build CFME. The assets directory is now available as expected.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1079887">1079887</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>The virtual machines configuration management report was querying the incorrect data field when looking up the number of available vCPUs in a virtual machine. This meant that the Cloud Forms Management Engine was not reporting the number of vCPUs correctly when integrated with the Red Hat Enterprise Virtualization product. The virtual machines configuration management report was changed to query the correct data field. Additional changes were also made to ensure that accurate data is available in this field. The number of vCPUs are now reported correctly in the virtual machines configuration management report.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1072113">1072113</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>When a user only had access to Services trees saw their VMs in a dashboard widget and clicked on them, they were directed to Infrastructure / Virtual Machines rather than Services / Workloads. A blank screen with no results displayed, and the production.log showed the following error message :

FATAL -- : Error caught: [RuntimeError] User is not allowed to access Virtual Machines, please contact your Administrator

This fix adds code to redirect users to the workloads explorer from the dashboard widget if they do not have access to accordions in the VM Infrastructure or VM Cloud explorers.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=984774">984774</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the previous version of CloudForms Management Engine, orphaned templates were listed when attempting to create a catalog. Selecting an orphaned template resulted in the error that the template was orphaned and could not be used for provisioning. This bug was fixed by filtering out orphaned templates from the list of available templates displayed while creating a catalog. As a result of this change, the user no longer encounters the orphaned template error when creating a catalog.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1095467">1095467</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the older version of Cloud Forms Management Engine, generating a custom report resulted in the error "No class found for explorer tree node type 2". This was because the custom report was queued with incorrect options for the tree view system. This bug was fixed by queuing custom reports with the correct options for the tree view system. Users are now able to run custom reports as required.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1060315">1060315</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Previously, browsing the 5.2.1.8 user interface using an Internet Explorer 8 browser resulted in an "Error 403 Forbidden Page" error. Internet Explorer does not set a page referer by default when using the page.redirect_to method. This fix sets the referer via javascript when page.redirect_to is called and redirects to the correct URL.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1095398">1095398</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the older version of Cloud Forms Management Engine, an unexpected error "Class 'NilClass' is not eligible for classification" was encountered while editing CFME server relationship for a virtual machine. This was because of incorrect parameters being passed to the tag retrieval function. This issue was fixed by passing in the correct parameters to the tag retrieval function. Users are now able to edit CFME server relationship for any virtual machine as expected.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1058450">1058450</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>During the migration of VMware virtual machines, a type error caused the migration to fail with a UI error. This was caused by a refactor of the allowed_ci method in vm_migrate_workflow, which required sub-classed models to override and pass a list of sources. The call has been fixed, and virtual machine migration succeeds.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1061482">1061482</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the older version of Cloud Forms Management Engine, generating a PDF from the Infrastructure or Providers pages resulted in an user interface error. This was due to missing information critical for generating the PDFs. This bug was fixed by adding in the missing information required for generating the PDFs. PDFs can now be generated as expected from the Infrastructure or Providers pages.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1057753">1057753</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>When adding a user's email id to receive an alert when a VM's memory allocation was increased, an undefined method error was generated. This error was fixed in the latest version of CFME. Users can now be successfully added to receive email alerts when a VM's memory allocation is increased.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1057399">1057399</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the older version of Cloud Forms Management Engine, the button to access the console for a VM hosted on VMWare vSphere was disabled in certain Internet explorer and Chrome browser versions. It was enabled but crashed the browser in Firefox. These browser issues were fixed in the new version of Cloud Forms Management Engine, so that the console button is now enabled correctly.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=997911">997911</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In Control > Explorer > Policy, creating a policy with event as "Host Auth Error" or "Host Auth. Incomplete Credentials" that is associated with an action, does not trigger policies associated with the events. In the expected scenarios, events host_auth_error or host_auth_incomplete are not getting raised, and always call the "host_auth_invalid" instead.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1094884">1094884</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the older version of Cloud Forms Management Engine, editing the meta data for any PXE boot image resulted in the error, 'undefined local variable or method', as a result the meta data edit failed. This bug was due to a typographic error in the code. The bug was fixed by correcting the coding error, allowing users to edit PXE boot image meta data as expected.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1057396">1057396</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>When users belonging to more than one LDAP group attempted switching from one group to another via the CFME user interface, the user interface either denied access or resulted in a white screen. An HTTP referer check has been implemented to check for privileges and the session referer is now saved when a user switches groups. The user switching groups should now see the dashboard for the target user group.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1072494">1072494</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>When objects were passed to automate with a URL it instantiated the base_class model which ignored subclasses and methods exposed through subclassed service models. This meant that subclass methods were not available to automate scripts. Bugs in method overriding and association while loading the correct subclass when instantiating a service model were fixed and subclass methods are now available to automate scripts.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1002671">1002671</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>The previous versions of CloudForms Management Engine did not include support for tenant users and projects other then the admin account and its projects from Red Hat OpenStack. This issue was fixed by adding the ability to import tenant information from openstack and expose that information when provisioning a new VM. The CFME administrator now needs to map the imported tenants to CFME users. The CFME appliance in turn uses a single OpenStack admin user to access resources on OpenStack on behalf of its users.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1132708">1132708</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the older version of Cloud Forms Management Engine, a fatal error was encountered when attempting to edit ISO image meta data in the ISO datastore for PXE controllers. This was fixed by adding in missing route information for editing ISO image metadata. ISO image metadata can now be edited as expected.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1131330">1131330</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In Service, when creating a catalog item, or in Cloud > Instances > Provision Instances, clicking on the Properties page, threw an error: "undefined method '[]' for nil:NilClass [miq_request/prov_field_changed]"

Code has been fixed and there is no error reported. The issue is now resolved.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1102388">1102388</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the older version of Cloud Forms Management Engine, the drift analysis page for virtual machines did not display any data. This was due to an issue with the filters used with the data visualization tool. The bug was fixed by correctly specifying the filters for the data visualization tool. The drift analysis page now displays the expected data for the selected virtual machine.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1007050">1007050</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the older version of Cloud Forms Management Engine, there were formatting errors when displaying check boxes in the accordions under the Infrastructure main menu. Multiple check boxes were shown on some lines, while no descriptive text accompanied other checkboxes. This was fixed by correcting the formatting information for these controls. The check boxes are now displayed correctly in the new version of Cloud Forms Management Engine.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1072082">1072082</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Adding a nil virtual column to a report resulted in failure to run the report. This was fixed by adding a test case for a nil virtual column, and reports containing a nil virtual column can now be run successfully.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1009347">1009347</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the older version of Cloud Forms Management Engine, a policy with the event "Host Added to Cluster" associated with a RHEV cluster did not trigger when a new host was added to the cluster. This was because there were no recognized RHEV events that could trigger this policy event. This was fixed by moving the host/cluster evm alert logic to the host, so that the event was triggered when the ems_cluster_id field changed on a host. The "Host Added to Cluster" policy now works as expected.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1054382">1054382</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>An error in the miq_widget code caused dashboard widgets not to update for users who were members of multiple LDAP groups. The widget code has been fixed, and widget content now updates correctly when multi-group users log in or switch their group contexts.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1052924">1052924</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Clicking the update button in the CFME appliance successfully registered and subscribed to the Satellite 5 server but failed to update due to yum not importing RPM GPG keys automatically from within the worker context. The keys are now imported prior to running the yum command, and the update succeeds.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1073689">1073689</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>The CloudInit customization template had an incorrect filename which resulted in the error when querying for the list of customization templates. Trying to query available customization templates from an automate script method while provisioning a cloud image resulted in an 'uninitialized constant' error. This fix was implemented by correcting the filename of CloudInit customization template service model. The automate script is now able to query for customized templates correctly.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1052069">1052069</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Group filters were not taking effect on group dashboards, allowing users to see information that should not be visible to the group. userids were not being passed in the rbac.search method call when widgets were being rendered for groups. This fix allows userids to always pass to the widget regardless of group or user.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1068705">1068705</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>The correct workflow subclass was not loaded when provisioning a virtual machine from ISO images using automate, causing eligible customization templates to be unavailable. The provisioning workflow has been updated to accept object or ids for templates. Additionally, the provisioning workflow was also changed to load the subclassed workflow instance based on the source template type. All eligible customization templates are now visible when provisioning an instance.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1122712">1122712</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the previous version of CloudForms Management Engine, attempting to clone a template resulted in the error "Migrate doesn't apply to templates". This was due to the wrong method being used for cloning the template. This bug was fixed by adding a new method to enable cloning of templates. Cloning templates now works as expected.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1016273">1016273</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the older version of Cloud Forms Management Engine, adding a dynamic drop down list without an entry point field in a new Automate dialog resulted in an undefined method error. This was fixed by requiring the entry point field for the dynamic drop down list, and displaying a flash message if the entry point field was not provided. The Automate dialog can now be created correctly.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1050211">1050211</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>The older version of Cloud Forms Management Engine shipped with platform updates disabled, requiring users to update packages manually on the command line. Platform updates were disabled on all appliances, as updates to postgres and other database packages could cause the CFME application services to be interrupted, requiring planned downtime. The new version of Cloud Forms Management Engine allows system updates on non database appliances, thus reducing the requirement to manually update these systems. Cloud Forms Management Engine appliances running a database are still required to be updated manually.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1018214">1018214</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Setting valid Remote Login credentials for an ESX host then attempting to validate the credentials in the Default Credentials section caused a "No credentials defined" error. The only way to add credentials for an ESX host was to use the default credentials of root, which required ssh login as root to be setup on ESX. This presents security risks. A clean up of auth_cache and related callbacks in the authentication mixin fixes the issue and users are now able to save login information.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1102822">1102822</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In Cloud > Reports > Dashboard Widgets > Charts, clicking on "Guest OS Information" and "Generate Widget content now". Content generation fails with an error status.

Fixed to change chart type from pie 3D to pie for predefined reports. "Guest OS Information" widget content can now be successfully generated.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1135497">1135497</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the older version of Cloud Forms Management Engine, deleting the selected tab while customizing an Automate service dialog resulted in an undefined method error. This was fixed by correctly defining the class for the affected object. The Automate service dialog can now be customized correctly.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1091962">1091962</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Certain browsers limit the size of the cookie field in the HTTP header. This used to lead to bad requests after navigating through a large number of pages, as the Cookie field of the HTTP header used to get filled up with cookies storing state information on the tree branches navigated to earlier. This was fixed by limiting the maximum size of cookies, so that cookies do not grow larger then the maximum size expected by browsers.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1019634">1019634</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the older version of Cloud Forms Management Engine, a policy defined for "VM Memory was increased" did not get triggered when the memory for a virtual machine that the policy was associated with was increased. This was due to an incorrect comparison order of the prior and current memory configuration. This was fixed by correcting the comparison order in the method that handled hardware reconfiguration. As a result of this, policies defined for "VM Memory was increased" are now triggered correctly.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=976426">976426</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the older versions of Cloud Forms Management Engine, the weekly top memory consumers report did not report any data if the user running the report did not have a time profile in their environment with a timezone that was set to “Roll Up Daily Performance”. This bug was fixed by removing the time zone requirement from all out of the box reports. The weekly top memory consumers report now works as expected.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1020985">1020985</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the older version of Cloud Forms Management Engine, selecting a provider from the providers list view using its quad icon resulted in the error "Page doesn't exist". This was due to an incorrect hyperlink being generated for the quad icon. This bug was fixed by correcting the code to generate the correct hyperlink for the quad icon. Selecting a provider using the quad icon now works as expected.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1071360">1071360</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>For users who were member of multiple LDAP groups, dashboard widget 'Guest OS Information' regeneration failed with an Error status. Also, "Virtual Infrastructure Platforms" and "Vendor and Guest OS Chart" were stuck at "Running" status with an error message on web UI, "Widget Generation for 5 of 2 groups Complete".

The Widget.get_group method has been updated to work with both group ID and description, and time out of active and creating miq_tasks when queuing the widget generation have been fixed. Dashboard widgets can now be successfully (re)generated for multi-group users.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1090028">1090028</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>A regression error caused the configuration button for PXE images to disappear. The code has been fixed and the missing PXE image product features have been added. The configuration button is now present.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1075251">1075251</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>There was a bug in matching the user's 'subscription types' attribute value to the preset values, resulting in an undefined method error when trying to register through the GUI on the Red Hat Updates tab. When editing user registration on the Red Hat Updates tab, the user is presented with  an 'undefined method '+' for nil:NilClass' error. The user was not able to complete registration. The fix was implemented by changing symbol matching to strings matching against the SUBSCRIPTION_TYPES constant value. The user is now able to complete registration successfully.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1045215">1045215</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Attempting to run the $evm.root['service'].inspect_all command caused an undefined method 'service_type' error, and the field service_type data failed to return. The service_type method and related code have been moved to the service_template model, and the command returns the expected data.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=965889">965889</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>The default log depot for Cloud Forms Management Engine has been moved from customer.manageiq.com to dropbox.redhat.com/incoming to allow Red Hat support associates access to logs uploaded by the appliance.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1077355">1077355</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Starting a console session using the VMRC 5.1 plugin console access only worked with a Firefox 27 browser, but failed on Internet Explorer 10, 11, and Chrome 19 with an error message.

Error message: Remote Console plugin is not properly installed

VMRC plugin version 5.1 was enabled in Internet Explorer and Chrome and a console session now starts correctly.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=965881">965881</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>A code refactor caused HyperV inventory collection to fail. The code changes have been reverted and collection now works correctly.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1141975">1141975</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Previously, switching a summary screen from textual to graphical mode did not work because the URL parameters were not sufficiently updating. Now, the update_url_parms method has been updated to handle parsing of multiple URL parameters and switching to graphical mode works as expected.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1087921">1087921</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In order to enable customers to read storage reports more easily, a new feature has been implemented for snapshot size to be available as Suffixed Bytes (B, KB, MB, GB) like other disk-related columns are (for example, total provisioned space and disk capacity), instead of just a number.

The format of the columns Snapshot Oldest Total Size and Snapshot Newest Total Size is now changed from Number (1,234) to Suffixed Bytes (B, KB, MB, GB). Thereby, the storage report is now easier to read in Suffixed Bytes format.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1114756">1114756</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the older version of Cloud Forms Management Engine, the administrator was not able to save a script as a component of a new customization template under the PXE option of the Infrastructure main menu. This was fixed by adding a missing variable in the customization template code. The customization template script can now be saved as expected.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1087637">1087637</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>The error is caused due to Automate generating incorrect XML. The CPU definition contained the unrecognised elements 'sockets'and 'cores' which are attributes of the topology element. Hence, after upgrading RHEVm from 3.3 to 3.4, the user cannot provision new VMs from CloudForms Management Engine. The RHEVm log contains the error 'unexpected element (uri:"", local:"sockets")'.
A number of fixes were incorporated to ensure that the CPU definition is generated correctly.
The user is now able to provision new VMs from CFME.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1044740">1044740</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>A new version of Prince, used to generate CSS styled PDF reports, was implemented in the CFME Appliance. The updated version could not find the path to the CSS file required to format generate the PDF documents correctly, resulting in simple tables of black text with blue page headers rather than matching the style of HTML reports. The fix sets relative paths, so the CSS file can be found by Price and PDFs are generated correctly.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1025567">1025567</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the beta release of Cloud Forms Management Engine 5.3, when ordering a service that presented a dialog to the user, the Submit and Cancel buttons were not shown, only the paging controls were shown. This bug was fixed by ensuring that the submit and cancel buttons were displayed as required, allowing users to order services as expected.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1077793">1077793</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Connection issues between the CFME appliance and vCenter hosts caused closed connections to remain idle instead of terminating. This has been fixed and sessions now close correctly.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1087476">1087476</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the beta version of CloudForms Management Engine 5.3, if an infrastructure provider was removed, then added again, the relationships between the provider and its clusters and hosts were not refreshed. This was because, the old provider information was not deleted from host records when the provider was deleted. When the same infrastructure provider was added back and a refresh was initiated, the hosts could not resolve provider information and got an object not found error. This bug was fixed by nullifying the provider information on hosts when deleting the provider. Now, when the provider is added back, the hosts look up provider information as expected.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1026415">1026415</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>After taking a snapshot of a virtual machine with the memory snapshot option enabled, the virtual machine shuts down when the snapshot is reverted to. The code has been updated to include the memory parameter when taking a snapshot. The virtual machine will now be in the state it was when the snapshot was taken.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1077859">1077859</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>When a user received the below links (vm_or_template, miq_request) via email they could no longer browse to a service / request page without having to manually navigate to the request queue and clicking on their request.
Logging into the CFME as an Admin and accessing the following URLs links resulted in a blank page: https://10.3.76.102/vm_or_template/show/619000000000068 and/or https://10.3.76.102/miq_request/show/619000000000079

White listing of entry points was implemented to the web UI which has fixed the issue. Upon clicking a service/request URL via email, user now gets to the desired correct page.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1079459">1079459</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Sorting a search result list of virtual machines by Provider was raising an unexpected error. The ambiguous 'type' PGError issue that was encountered when sorting by Provider has been fixed, and the search result list can now be sorted by Provider.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1059272">1059272</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>After logging in to the CFME and adding an infrastructure provider, in Infrastructure > Virtual Machines, clicking on a sort order such as sort on Hosts, Providers or Datastore columns in "VMs and Templates" accordion
resulted in a database error. This was because the SQL being used had an error for certain queries.

The code has been fixed and there is no error reported when using the above sorts.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1069026">1069026</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>CloudForms Management Engine failed to pull network information from OpenStack instances with multiple network interfaces. This caused network information to not appear through automate methods. This fix modifies the provisioning code for OpenStack instances to allow for an array of network interfaces. CloudForms now pulls network information for OpenStack instances with multiple interfaces.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1039971">1039971</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Editing certain expressions from the Control Explorer caused the following error: "undefined method 'index' for nil:NilClass [miq_policy/exp_changed]". This was due to certain keys remaining after discarding parts of the expression. This fix deletes the keys properly and fixes the observers for the date fields in the expression editor view. The expression editor now functions without error.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1028229">1028229</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Failure to uncompress parameter ids before running find caused an error when a user clicked on a non-VM file while browsing the datastore. The .find call has been fixed to uncompress the ids and non-VM files now work as expected when clicked.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1080231">1080231</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>User was unable to save "Remote Login" credentials for hypervisors with an error displayed on the user interface.

Error: "Default User ID must be entered if a Remote Login or Web Services User ID is entered"

With a clean up of auth_cache and related callbacks in authentication mixin the issue has been fixed and remote login information can now be saved.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1085104">1085104</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>The state_machine gem used in the vm_scanning method created a database transaction block when processing states as automate was coded to not allow methods to run inside of a database transaction. This caused an SQL error when trying to execute an automation request. Calling asynchronous raise_synthetic_event methods for automate tasks from policies has been fixed, which circumvents the database transaction block issue.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1081342">1081342</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the older version of Cloud Forms Management Engine, if the end user had Infrastructure access he automatically had PXE configuration access. To resolve this, additional role based access control was added to allow restricted access to PXE configuration. The administrator is now able control a user's access to PXE configuration as required.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1082156">1082156</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>The Cloud Forms Management Engine environment incorrectly calculated the CPU chargeback rate using the number of sockets, instead of the number of virtual CPUs. The Cloud Forms Management Engine code was changed to calculate the CPU chargeback rate using the number of virtual CPUs instead of the number of sockets. The Cloud Forms Management Engine environment now calculates the CPU chargeback rate for Red Hat Enterprise Virtualization VMs correctly.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1099046">1099046</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the older version of Cloud Forms Management Engine, the configuration comparison page for virtual machines did not display any data. This was due to an issue with the way filters were specified for the data visualization tool. The bug was fixed by correctly specifying the filters for the data visualization tool. The drift analysis page now displays the comparison data for the selected virtual machines.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1083765">1083765</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the beta version of CloudForms Management Engine 5.3, adding or editing a catalog bundle resulted in an undefined method error in the catalog controller code. This bug was fixed by correcting the error in the catalog controller code. The user is now able to add or edit a catalog bundle as expected.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1030209">1030209</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Provisioning OpenStack instances with multiple tenant networks available resulted in an error: "Multiple possible networks found, use a Network ID to be more specific." This fix adds a dialog to select the tenant network when multiple tenant networks are available. The user now selects the tenant network for their OpenStack instances.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1083764">1083764</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In a previous version of CloudForms Management Engine, the link to the service summary screen for services listed under Service -> My Service were broken. This resulted in an undefined local variable or method error when the user tried to access a service. This issue was fixed by generating the correct links for the services list.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1038653">1038653</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>When CFME is used to request the creation of a virtual machine, creates the virtual machine instance but throws an error message, leading users to believe that the virtual machine was not created. This was caused by the state machine running post_create_destination twice. The initial one succeeds and the second one fails because it had already created the virtual machine. post_install_callback has been changed to only run the method once. Virtual machines should now be created without any errors.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1038399">1038399</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Administrator role permissions were incorrectly configured, resulting in the role being unable to access the Cloud -> Security Groups and Services -> Catalogs Explorer features. The administrator role has been updated to enable these permissions and access these features.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1083622">1083622</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>When switching between groups, instead of the default page assigned to the user, dashboard defaults even when the user does not have access rights.

Fixed code to redirect user to a screen that they have access to when user switches between groups. Moved code that sets start page url into its own common method so it can be used when switching between groups and when user first logs in. Also, added spec test for "start_url_for_user" method to ensure it returns correct url when switching between user's group which has fixed the issue.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1083062">1083062</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the older version of Cloud Forms Management Engine, adding, deleting or renaming a system image type from the PXE menu did not refresh the customization tree in the left pane. This issue was fixed by enforcing an update of the customization template tree when adding, deleting or renaming a system image type. Users now see an updated customization template tree after making a system image type change.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1083465">1083465</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the beta release of Cloud Forms Management Engine 5.3, sub module icons displayed in the left pane next to sub module names were out of scale, making the list of sub modules harder to browse. This was fixed by pre-compiling the icons during the build phase, making it easy to browse the list of sub modules.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1068804">1068804</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Changes in the Red Hat Enterprise Virtualization 3.3 API allowed for deployment of multiple payloads in one API call. However, CloudForms Management Engine could not save payloads to virtual machines because the code focused on a single payload per call (3.2 and below). This fix adds an exception for Red Hat Enterprise Virtualization 3.3 that accommodates the API changes. CloudForms Management Engine now correctly interfaces with the Red Hat Enterprise Virtualization 3.3 API payload functions.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1035028">1035028</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Users with limited permissions received a blank page when attempting to view items in the Virtual Machines sub-tab under the Infrastructure tab. The feature check for the Virtual Machines sub-tab has been updated to enable users with limited access to view permitted features.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1035197">1035197</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>If a user was in a time zone for which roll up information was not available, running utilization summary or performance reports gave an unexpected error with the explanation: missing attribute: timestamp. This caused utilization summaries and performance reports to stop working for the user. The issues with the time profiles pull down were fixed by changing the default time profile UTC and made read only. The utilization summaries and performance reports now work correctly.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1083397">1083397</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the older version of Cloud Forms Management Engine, adding or editing a service catalog resulted in an undefined method error. This was due to a coding error resulting from a change in the library handling dynamic trees. This bug was fixed by correcting the coding errors, allowing users to add or edit a service catalog as expected.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1035402">1035402</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In Automate -> Customization, editing a dynamic dialog without entering values in certain fields, and then attempting to Save it threw an error: undefined method ‘split’ for nil:NilClass [miq_ae_customization/dialog_edit].
Fixed code to provide an appropriate error message: "Entry Point must be given for field name”
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1104895">1104895</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the older version of Cloud Forms Management Engine, executing a new button on an existing service to run a method resulted in a fatal error: No route matches. This was because a route to dynamically refresh the service controller was missing. This issue was fixed by adding in this missing route. Executing a new button on an existing service now works as expected.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1036469">1036469</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the previous version of CloudForms Management Engine, when editing a virtual machine template, moving a virtual machine from the list of available virtual machines to the left or right could result in the fatal error, comparison of Array with Array failed. This bug was fixed by verifying that the hash of choices chosen to verify the chosen choice existed prior to processing the lists on either side. Virtual machine templates can now be edited without any errors.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1126071">1126071</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the previous version of CloudForms Management Engine, the smart proxy executable was not uploaded to the appliance during start-up. This was due to the presence of a newline at the end of the VERSION file. The newline caused the comparison of the rpm version with the version provided by the smart proxy executable to fail, resulting in the failed upload. This bug was fixed by adding code to strip off any leading or trailing white space from the VERSION file. The smart proxy executable is now available in the appliance as expected.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1047348">1047348</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Added 'IP Address' column to VM views so users can see a VM's IP address when logging in with a user_self_service role.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1083198">1083198</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>A missing uniqueness check enabled multiple system image types to be saved with identical names. The pxe_image_type method has been updated to validate uniqueness and display a flash message when the test fails. Attempting to use an existing name now fails with a duplicate name error.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1083149">1083149</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>An incorrect method call meant that after adding or removing policy profiles on the virtual machine policy simulation screen, the vertical scrollbar disappeared from the VM explorer. The page.replace call has been replaced with page.replace_html, and the scrollbar now appears correctly.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1033619">1033619</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the previous version of CloudForms Management Engine, on the host information page, the install_failed state did not have an icon. This bug was fixed by adding the missing “Install Failed” icon. The host information field now shows the correct icon when installation fails for a host.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1083693">1083693</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Missing tag removal capabilities meant that tags could not be removed from VMDB objects in automate. This ability has been added and tags can now be unassigned in automate.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1083761">1083761</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the previous version of CloudForms Management Engine, when adding a custom button group the group button name text field did not get focus until clicked. This was due to a conflict in the Java script code. This was fixed by moving the Javascript code to another DHTML tag. The group button name text field now gets focus on page load as expected.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1082569">1082569</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>The correct search options were not passed to the query when reloading a VM filter with user input, causing an error. The filter dialog was changed to show a quick search pop up box when the Reload button is pressed to prompt for the user's input. The custom VM filter can now be reloaded successfully.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1084214">1084214</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the beta version of CloudForms Management Engine 5.3, the login page did not check for a custom login logo correctly. This resulted in the login logo not being displayed on the login page. This bug was fixed by correcting the login logo check. The login logo is now displayed on the login page as expected.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1084634">1084634</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the beta version of CloudForms Management Engine 5.3, running a web based VMRC session for a virtual machine that had a tag assigned resulted in an undefined local variable or method fatal error. This bug was fixed by re-basing the CloufForms Management Engine code base to the latest upstream version.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1028618">1028618</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the beta version of CloudForms Management Engine 5.3, when the mouse pointer was hovered over the accordions in the explorer views, it did not change to a hand pointer, it stayed as a normal pointer image. This issue was fixed by adding CSS styling to add hand pointer. Now when the mouse is hovered over the accordions, it changes to a hand pointer.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1027396">1027396</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Registration with Red Hat Network (RHN) Satellite failed. 90 seconds after clicking Register, an error appeared in the evm.log and the server was not registered with RHN. Calls to Rhn#register now correctly use the server certificate, and the server successfully registers and subscribes to RHN.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1026975">1026975</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the beta version of CloudForms Management Engine 5.3, the
Report Menu Editor failed and resulted in a blank area when moving selected reports up/down. Additionally, pressing move up/down buttons with an available report selected resulted in an undefined local variable or method error. These issues were introduced during refactoring of code to use presenter class. This issue is fixed in the current version of CFME. No error is displayed when moving selected reports up/down or pressing move up/down buttons with an available report.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1086275">1086275</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the beta version of CloudForms Management Engine 5.3, the background image was not scaled correctly and did not occupy the entire window in Internet Explorer 8. This was because the correct image path was not provided. This bug was fixed by providing the correct path for the background image. The background image is now rendered correctly in Internet Explorer 8.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1078523">1078523</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>When logging into the CFME appliance, dashboard widgets were unable to display data due to failure to check the current region for a user.
Code update enabled search on the user in the current region, and widgets now display data correctly and the issue is fixed.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1078496">1078496</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>After creating a control policy, invoking an action based on an event for the assigned policy, then navigating back to Control, Explorer displays a blank screen, and the user cannot navigate to Control, Explorer after policy enforcement. Fixed the folder_get_info method to not call policy_get_all when selected node in policy tree is a policy or an event, as there was no need to get/display list of policies on those nodes. Calling the policy_get_all method was setting a @edit in the get_view method which was preventing views to be drawn correctly when returning back to explorer. The policy_get_all method only needs to be called when VM XX Policies or Host XX policies nodes are selected in the tree, to display list of policies. This has fixed the issue and user is now able to navigate to Control, Explorer after policy enforcement.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1118726">1118726</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Logged in as a new user with assigned support role, in Cloud Intelligence > Reports, selecting a report from All Reports, and attempting to add a new schedule for the user with support role results in an error: The user is not authorized for this task or item. [report/x_button]
Added schedule view feature so that users can see schedules accordion even when they are not allowed to modify scheduled records. This has now fixed the issue.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1087520">1087520</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the previous version of CloudForms Management Engine, attempting to add a new name space under Automate -> Explorer in Internet Explorer 8 resulted in a blank page. This bug was fixed by re-basing to a new upstream version of CloudForms Management Engine. Adding a new name space using Internet Explorer 8 now works as expected.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1044175">1044175</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Need persistent workspace i.e allowing a variable on the root hash ($evm.root['ae_workspace'] to enable storing data when dealing with ae_retry in automate.

Code  updated to persist automate state data between retries. During the execution of an automate method the following three methods can be called to set/get/check for existence of state data.
$evm.set_state_var
$evm.get_state_var
$evm.state_var_exist?

The name in all three functions above can be a string or a symbol. If the name is missing nil is returned.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1024988">1024988</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>White space around new user names allowed user names to be added multiple times. A code fix has been applied that strips white space from around user names and email addresses.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1024059">1024059</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the previous version of CloudForms Management Engine, even though the initial Configuration / Tasks screen had second level navigation, they did not appear when switching between tabs on Tasks screen.
This issue was fixed by fixing the view code that sets second level active/inactive tabs.
This issue is fixed in the current version of CFME to show second level navigation when switching between tabs.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1023540">1023540</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the previous version of CloudForms Management Engine, the console access button for virtual machines hosted on a VMWare provider was unavailable in MacOS X browsers. This was confusing for Macintosh users, as they expected console functionality to be available. This issue was resolved by displaying a disabled console button, with an informative message when the mouse pointer hovered over the button.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1087930">1087930</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Incorrect values were passed to the methods that created the combo boxes in the schema editor screen. Deleting a class field in the schema editor resulted in an undefined method error. The code was fixed to pass correct values to the combo box methods and deleting a class field works now correctly.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1023226">1023226</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the previous version of CloudForms Management Engine user interface, incorrect flash message is displayed after successfully setting ownership of RHOS instances. This issue was fixed when code change was applied to properly parse object type name and pluralize it. In the current version of CFME, correct message is displyed.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1023220">1023220</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In Infrastructure > Providers > Select a Provider; under 'Relationships' accordion, clicking on Virtual Machines and selecting multiple VMs for which ownership needs to be set and setting ownership Configuration > Set Ownership, redirected to 'VMs and Instances' page after ownership of VMs is successfully set, instead of 'All VMs' page of the corresponding provider or host.

Fixed navigation code in Set Ownership page to go back to All VMs page, and not to VMs and Instances page. This has now resolved the issue.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1023177">1023177</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the previous version of CloudForms Management Engine user interface, there used to be a timeline button for Amazon provider and instances. Amazon does not provide the feature for which timelines are used. Hence, the Timeline option button was removed from Amazon providers. The current version of CFME does not have a Timeline option under Amazon Provider.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1045325">1045325</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Performing an analyze check compliance policy on a host linked from another CloudForms entities (e.g. Providers) caused the following error: "undefined method 'sub_table' for nil:NilClass". This fix adds "Analyze then Check Compliance" button support when navigating to the list of hosts from another CloudForms entity. No error display and the "Analyze then Check Compliance" launches successfully.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1037835">1037835</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>A problem parsing hash keys caused an undefined method error when attempting to run a planning task with manual data. Hash keys are now read correctly, and planning tasks can be run using manual data.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1047976">1047976</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Navigating second and third level elements in the Control Explorer policy trees leaves the right cell header text unchanged. This fix assigns the correct value to the right cell header, which now changes according to the element selected.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1048390">1048390</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>When attempting to view a comparison of the Parent Host and the CloudForms virtual machine under Configure > Diagnostics > Utilization Tab, an undefined method error resulted.  The user interface would attempt to display a chart based on the internal representation of the vmrecord which was not consistent with the internal index used by the web interface. To fix this, the charts are now based off of the MiqServer server records. The utilization graphs should now display.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1076717">1076717</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>The ServiceTemplate service model class was missing associations for service_templates, services and service_resources. The required associations in the ServiceTemplate service model have been updated and are now available in automate.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1142281">1142281</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Previously, users could not switch between Grid-Tile-List views in Tenant Instance screens because the buttons were missing from those sub-lists. These buttons have since been added so that users can switch between views.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1076609">1076609</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>When you create a state machine, edit the schema and add a new field, the default value gets populated in the newly created field from the previous field. Plus, the data type also gets populated in the newly created field from the previous field. The code was updated to reset the new_field hash after the accept button is pressed on the schema edit screen. When new AE Fields are added values no longer get copied over from the previous field. Also, the substitute checkbox now has an initial value and the data type of second field is now a password data type.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1022202">1022202</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the previous version of CloudForms Management Engine, PDF downloads did not work from the cloud provider textual summary screen. This bug was introduced when cloud providers were broken out of the infrastructure providers. This bug was fixed by adding the relevant options to the cloud provider summary screen. PDF downloads from the cloud provider summary screen now work as expected.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1090901">1090901</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the beta version of CloudForms Management Engine 5.3, if the last role or group authorizing a user's access to the CloudForms appliance was deleted, the login screen hung indefinitely and an undefined method error was logged in the production log. This bug was fixed by changing the login screen to show a message that the user's role or group may have been deleted from database. The login screen no longer hangs indefinitely when the user's role or group has been deleted.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1017917">1017917</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the previous version of CloudForms Management Engine, editing a service request incorrectly brought up the virtual machine reconfigure dialog resulting in an unrelated error message referring to memory. This was an error in the work flow as service requests may not be edited. This was fixed by hiding the edit button for all service template provisioning requests. Service requests can not be edited in the current version of CloudForms Management Engine.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1075150">1075150</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Cloud archived instances were showing up where they shouldn’t. Cloud archived instances showed up under its cloud provider instance tree, cloud instances archived tree, as well as infrastructure archived tree.
The code has been fixed to load Infra only VMs and Templates in tree and list view - Changed code to pass in where_clause when building a list views for Archived/Orphaned nodes in VMs and Templates accordion. Also, changed x_get_tree_custom_kids method to get records using VmInfra and TemplateInfra db instead of VmOrTemplate to get Infra only nodes for the VMs and Templates tree Archived/Orphaned nodes. These changes have now resolved the issue.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1146613">1146613</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>The beta version of CloudForms Management Engine 5.3 had a logical error in the user interface for creating a custom button. After editing the custom button, the Save button would not be enabled unless the user clicked somewhere else. This was because the custom button were missing the Intervals parameter. This bug was fixed by updating the custom button user interface to provide the Intervals parameter for custom buttons. The Save button is now enabled correctly for the custom button interface.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1074495">1074495</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Attempting to configure RHEL OSP 4.0 AMQP in CloudForms caused an SASL error:
> Internal-error: Sasl error: SASL (-4) no mechanism available: No worthy mechs found (qpid/SaslFactory.cpp:280)
This patch changes the default connection mechanism to AMQP to enforce SSL, which enables CFME to collect events from OpenStack where the AMQP service is listening for SSL connections. The fix changes the default AMQP port to 5671, and users must populate the /etc/qpid/certs directory. To use non-SSL for AMQP, set the port to 5672.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1011263">1011263</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In Automate > Customization > Button, creating a button group and adding button with a hover text, and then adding another button with the same hover text threw a validation error: “Error during 'add': Description has already been taken".
Description attribute has been added to locales/en.yml, and changed method to full_message, when calling add_flash. So, the description has now been replaced with button hover text, that is displayed in flash message. These changes have fixed the issue.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1011262">1011262</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>The text cursor is set to button name, but upon starting to type in text, the UI refreshed and the user had to click on the text box again to enter the name. Although it seemed that the button text had focus, it did not have focus and clicking the button had a conflict with the Button Image drop down (which uses the DHTMLXcombo control).
Code has been updated and the focus on button text now works as expected.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1053754">1053754</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>When a third level folder was selected on the Policy tree and the tree nodes were expanded to the fourth level, the cell header on the right panel assigned the label of "Host Control Node" erroneously to a VM-controlled Node. This was fixed in the current version of cfme. The right panel cell header now correctly displays the right label.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1011158">1011158</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>The Approve button appeared for previously denied requests, however approving denied requests resulted in an error. This fix removes the Approve button for denied requests. Users can no longer attempt to approve a denied request.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1073673">1073673</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>When creating a CloudInit customization template the UI still reported that it was a type of Sysprep although it was created as a CloudInit type.

Code was updated and the customization template type will now be displayed based on the @ct.type which has fixed the issue.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1007581">1007581</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In a previous version of CloudForms Management Engine, switching the user's group context in Firefox browser failed due to a javascript error. This issue was fixed by modifying the on-click event handler for the group context switcher pull-down. Firefox users are now able to change their group context as expected.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1002307">1002307</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In a previous verison of CFME, in the Add a new dialog window, under Automate -> Customization, when a user tried to provide a label and click submit, he got an error message: Dialog label required. This issue was fixed with a change in the code.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1001285">1001285</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>The previous version of CloudForms Management Engine had an option to automatically choose the host and storage for provisioning a virtual machine. The automatic provisioning of virtual machines could fail with an error stating that a suitable host was not found, if no hosts with the provisioning scope tag were present in the selected provider. This issue was fixed by a change in the default automatic host selection logic which did not rely on tagging. Automatic provisioning of virtual machines now works as expected.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=997201">997201</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>UI labels, such as From Automate, Customization, click the Service Dialogs Accordion, did not have consistent capitalization.

The yml file containing Dialogs action texts was modified: Refactored dialog_center_tb.yml to use .titleize; replaced .capitalize with .titleize for display of deleted object names.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=996787">996787</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the previous version of CloudForms Management Engine, it was possible to create a duplicate automate custom service dialog. This was because there was no validation in place to enforce unique dialog names. This was fixed by adding dialog label validation to enforce uniqueness. It is no longer possible to create duplicate automate custom service dialogs.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=995147">995147</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the Automate -> Simulation tab, requested output is available in a tree view, XML view and object. The XML view output can be long and usually takes more than the standard length of the screen page to display completely. However there was no vertical scroll bar to view the entire output.

Code was updated to fix the scrolling issue and the complete output can now be viewed.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=991595">991595</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In Services > Catalogs, creating a new catalog item and selecting "Generic", the “Basic Info” tab appeared to have been cut at the end lacking the rounded finish. After selecting the "Display in Catalog" check box, the page refreshed after a while, and the "Details" tab appeared alongside the “Basic Info” tab.

New tab design has been implemented which has now fixed the issue.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1095651">1095651</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the beta version of CloudForms Management Engine 5.3, deleting the last custom report from list of reports under the Intelligence main menu item resulted in an undefined method error. The report, however was deleted. This error was a result of the reports tree view not handling the case where custom reports were not present. This bug was fixed by removing redundant code and adding a check for the case where no custom reports were present in the reports list. Deletion of custom reports now works as expected.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=986934">986934</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Previously in the CloudForms Management Engine user interface under Control tab -> Explorer -> Alerts accordion, there were some configurable alerts which sent emails from the CloudForms administrator to a Manage IQ email address. This email address has now been disabled.
This issue was fixed by disabling the default recipient id of alert@manageiq.com. The administrator is now required to configure the alerts email recipient id for alerts to work correctly.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=985543">985543</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In Infrastructure > virtual machines, selecting a VM for reconfiguration and setting memory with default value as an integer in its option displays an error message -"Memory must be an integer", although the default value of memory is an integer. This was due to memory value getting set as a string when user entered value in the form and transaction got sent up.

Changed reconfigure_build_screen method to set default memory/CPU value to nil/1 when multiple VMs are being reconfigured and they have different memory/CPU values. Also updated logic to not allow reconfiguring of VMs if the memory/CPU values are same as original values. And, verified that the correct default values are being set by set_memory_cpu method.  This has changed the way reconfigure sets default memory settings and this has fixed the issue and there is now a proper validation for the field: "Change Memory Value to submit reconfigure request".
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=983744">983744</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the previous version of CloudForms Management Engine, in the Services -> Requests view, the requesters pull-down list did not show the current user, but instead displayed a user whose requests the current user did not have permissions to view. This issue has been fixed in the current version. Requester pull down now displays the correct user.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1072089">1072089</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>When attempting to use the Integration / VimApi / VMware_HotAdd_Disk method to add a disk to a VM in VMware, a ruby error was generated and disk wasn’t being added.

The MiqVimVm#addDisk method was using the public accessor dsName2mo() when creating the ConfigSpec used to add a disk to the VM; causing the returned object to be wrapped in a MiqDrbReturn object. This caused the MiqDrbReturn object to be passed back to the client, since only top-level return objects should be wrapped in MiqDrbReturn. The client would then pass this unexpected object to the VMware VIM API, causing the failure.

Using the internal accessor dsName2mo_local() when acquiring sub-objects of the ConfigSpec, since this method does not wrap its returned value in a MiqDrbReturn object was the solution.

Also, fixed VMware service model methods for set_memory and add_disk; both method names were incorrectly set to an existing method name in a previous refactoring. This has fixed the issue and disk is  now being added to a VM in Vmware without any error.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=983735">983735</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In Services->Requests, dropdown did not display the correct user i.e. the current logged in user. The different user being displayed was due to the dropdown being in essence hard-coded to display one request type, and that user was the only user with a request of that type.

Passing in an array of the current request types instead of the hard coded value has resolved the issue and the dropdown now displays the correct logged in user.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1130666">1130666</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>This update fixes an issue where the retirement date for a service is able to be set in the past. This meant that a service could be retired showing a date in the past and it should not be able to be set to any date before the current date. The dhtmlXCalendarObject is now initialized in a way that it will not render allow past days to be selected. This means that the retirement date for a service can no longer be set to a date before the current date.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1062347">1062347</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>When attempting to connect to an external database, the password provided was being overwritten with the default DB password in config/database.yml after joining the region. This prevented the appliance from running since it could not connect to the DB.

Added fix_auth tool to upgrade user to a new encryption key which has fixed the issue.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1071970">1071970</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>When cloning a VM using automate, if there were any prov.set_network_adapter options found in the automation model, all NICs from the original template were removed in the destination VM and NICs were created according to what was specified in automate. A number of changes were made to ensure that the NICs from the Cloud Forms Management Engine dialogs exist with additional NICs from automate. NICs specified in the original template VM are now available in the clone, in addition to the NICs specified in automate.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1062391">1062391</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the previous version of CloudForms Management Engine, when only the custom logo image was selected, both the custom logo and custom login panel images were displayed. When only the custom login panel logo was selected, neither image was displayed. This was because the code that checked for the custom logo and custom login panel logo flags was flawed. The custom logo / login panel logo flag code was corrected to check for the appropriate flags. The custom logo and custom login panel logos are now displayed as per the administrator's selection.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=975389">975389</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the CloudFroms Management Engine user interface, when a user clicked on Management System-> Hosts-> VMs for the host
-> Check the box by the VM to retire -> Lifecycle -> Set Retirement Dates, the user was able to select a past date for the VM's retirement. Selecting a past date resulted in the VM powering off immediately. This issue was fixed by changing the date control options to limit what dates can be selected by the user.
Now, the user can only set a future retirement date for a VM.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1070860">1070860</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>The user interface did not check for a blank field list when switching to the Styling tab. When attempting to create a new report, if the user clicked on the Styling tab without selecting a field first, the user received the error: undefined method 'each_with_index' for nil:NilClass. The method has been updated, and the user interface now shows a flash message to force the user to select a field before changing to the Styling tab.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1069680">1069680</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>An error with port scanning logic caused VMware ESX host provisioning to fail. CloudForms Management Engine required availability of all defined ports instead of just one. This fix corrects the logic. CloudForms Management Engine's port scanner now only requires detection of a single port for ESX hosts.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1108918">1108918</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>If provisioning was configured to use a pre-provision dialog, it never progressed to the main provisioning dialog screen. This was due to an incorrect request workflow being followed. Several adjustments in the code were done to accommodate the pre-provisioning dialog prior to the main provisioning dialog in the request workflow. The pre-provisioning dialog now works as expected.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=962516">962516</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In Services > catalogs > create a catalog item and order, Save button was not functional; It was throwing an error message on the UI that the Save button is not yet implemented.

Code has been updated to remove all buttons except Submit and Cancel. Submit button has been implemented as a Save button function. Added support of default values for TextBox and TextAreaBox in Service Dialogs. These changes have now fixed the issue.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1065078">1065078</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>The Service Details page displayed the aggregate VM memory using the wrong factor. For example, instead of 512 megabytes, the page displayed 512 bytes. This fix corrects the factor representation of the memory. The memory now displays as megabytes instead of bytes.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=945417">945417</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In VM Explorer, LifeCycle > Clone selected item, and Publish selected item - These are hidden when you go to a summary screen for a RHEVM VM and  should also be hidden on the VM Explorer screen. However, clicking on them gave an error on the UI:
“Dialog cannot be found. Name:[miq_provision_redhat_dialogs_clone_to_vm] Type:[MiqProvisionWorkflow] [vm_or_template/x_button]”

Code was updated to remove the Clone and Publish buttons from list view. These buttons are not available in list view in workloads explorer, they are only available on summary screen so they can be turned on/off based upon type of record which has now resolved the issue.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1066207">1066207</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>When attempting to delete a Red Hat Enterprise Virtualization VM, Cloud Forms Management Engine would first attempt to stop the already stopped VM. This caused Red Hat Enterprise Virtualization to issue a "409 Resource Conflict" error, and the VM was not deleted. The cloud Forms Management Engine code was changed to correctly handle HTTP 409 and Resource Conflict errors from Red Hat Enterprise Virtualization. Cloud Forms Management Engine is now able to delete stopped Red Hat Enterprise Virtualization VMs.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1102397">1102397</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>The compare variable could contain a nil value when the panel_control action was run, which caused an unexpected error while applying drift sections on the VM scan page. This was fixed by setting the correct variable values when the accordions in compare/drift are clicked. The error condition is no longer encountered when selecting the drift accordion.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1052376">1052376</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Due to missing entries in the view configuration file, the Flavor and IP Addresses columns were not being displayed when viewing an Availability Zone in the explorer tree. The missing entries have been added to the file, and the Flavor and IP Addresses columns now display correctly.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=967096">967096</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>If a user used Internet Explorer to access the CloudForms Management Engine user interface, in the PXE-> Customization Template Area, the complete text could not be viewed in the edit boxes. This issue was fixed by editing the code in views to adjust the fomatting and DHTMLX layout for proper scrolling. Internet Explorer users can now view the complete text in the latest version of the CloudForms Management Engine user interface.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=979525">979525</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Vdi farm count is visible in wrench icon -> configuration tab -> settings accordion -> click specific_zone; Vdi zone farm count should be hidden behind yaml key.
Fixed code and the Vdi zone farm count is now hidden and the issue is resolved.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=983093">983093</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>The titles for policy items in the Control Explorer displayed "control" and "compliance" twice. For example, "Adding a new Control Host control Policy" should be "Adding a new Host Control Policy". This fix corrects the wording of the titles, which now display correctly.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=990635">990635</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Previously in the CloudForms Management Engine user interface, under VM details -> Monitoring -> Timelines, when a user selected an event group, he could view Virtual Desktop Infrastructure(VDI) activity, which should be hidden.
This issue was fixed by removing 'VDI Activity' in timeline options from Event Groups drop-down.
VDI activity is now hidden in timeline options -> event group drop-down.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=990702">990702</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Delete service dialog message shows the description instead of service dialog name. The message displayed after a delete should be consistent with other messages like add, save, cancel, etc and show the name of the dialog deleted.  The name used in all of these messages should match with what’s shown in the tree and the list views.

Code refactored dialogs_spec.rb which has now fixed the issue. The message now shows the name of the dialog deleted.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=990755">990755</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Delete service dialog message showed the description instead of service dialog name. The message displayed after a delete should be consistent with other messages like add, save, cancel, etc and show the name of the dialog deleted.  The name used in all of these messages should match with what’s shown in the tree and the list views.

Code refactored dialogs_spec.rb which has now fixed the issue. The message now shows the name of the dialog deleted.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=991143">991143</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>"Check Compliance of Last known Configuration" button was still active even if no compliance policies were assigned to a virtual machine. This fix adds logic to check for compliance policies assigned to a virtual machine. "Check Compliance of Last known Configuration" button is now disabled if a virtual machine has no compliance policies assigned to it.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1015663">1015663</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Queueing a report did not refresh the left menu tree. This fix adds code to refresh the "reports" and "save_reports" menu trees. The menu tree now refreshes to indicate the queued report.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1018963">1018963</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the previous version of CloudForms Management Engine, the spinner on the login page used to appear centered on the entire page, instead of appearing centered in the login form area. This bug was fixed by moving the spinner view into the login view. The spinner now appears centered in the login form area of the new version of CloudForms Management Engine.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1091958">1091958</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the beta version of CloudForms Management Engine 5.3, any flash messages displayed on a page did not scroll vertically with the page. This bug was fixed by changing the positioning property of all flash messages to be relative. Flash messages now scroll along with the page as expected.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1023488">1023488</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Previously, when the user accessed CloudForms Management Engine in Internet Explorer, the font in the navigation bar looked distorted since the font anti-aliasing was broken. This issue was fixed by implementing a new drop-down style secondary navigation.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1025847">1025847</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the previous version of CloudForms Management Engine, when users created a customized template in Infrastructure-> PXE-> customization template and tried to add a new customization template without selecting the "Image type", the message "customization template added" was displayed but the customization template would not be added. This was also observed while copying the customization templates.
This issue was fixed by refactoring code to account for blank/invalid Image Type setting. This issue is fixed in the current version of CFME. Now, if a user tries to add a customization template without selecting an image type, they are prompted to provide a PXE image type.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1086833">1086833</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the previous version of CloudForms Management Engine, the columns on the My Settings -> Default View page did not scale correctly under different screen resolutions. This was due to an incorrectly specified toolbar width in the cascading style sheet template. Removing the toolbar width in the cascading style sheet template resolved this issue. The Default Views setting page now renders correctly at all screen resolutions.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1026946">1026946</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the previous version of CloudForms Management Engine documentation, Integration Services Guide was referred to as Integrate Documentation.
This issue was fixed by fixing the link text for Integration Services Guide in the support view and updating view wording for the Integration Services Guide link.
The current documentation does not have this issue.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1038383">1038383</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>CloudForms Management Engine displays an "Abandon Changes" dialog box when clicking on a different tab after downloading a SmartProxy executable. This dialog box is unnecessary. This fix adds a hidden flag to the form to stop the dialog from appearing if not needed on a specific page. No "Abandon Changes" dialog appears when navigating to a different tab after downloading the SmartProxy executable.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1082609">1082609</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>The comment in the code of the EVM automate check_powered_off method is misleading.

Incorrect Description:
Notes: This method checks to see if the VM has been deleted from the VC.

The description of the check_powered_off automate method has been fixed and it now describes the method correctly.

Corrected Description:
Notes: This method checks to see if the VM has been powered off or suspended
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1050038">1050038</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the previous version of CloudForms Management Engine, the cloud intelligence charge back report could be grouped by virtual machines, this option was called VM. This report screen was updated to allow grouping by virtual machines or instances. The grouping option is now called VM/Instances.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1094490">1094490</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In Configure -> Configuration -> Access control, user group can be deleted while a user is still assigned. The model should not allow a group to be deleted if it is in use by a user.
Updated code to use before_destroy to ensure there are no associated users when deleting the group which has now resolved the issue. Error message while trying to delete a group with users assigned: EVM Group "test group": Error during 'destroy': Still has users assigned.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1052353">1052353</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Need support for cloud-init templates for RHEV clones. This is to utilize RHEV template cloning for VM provisioning. In order to provide customization of the cloned Vms, it would be helpful if CFME could pass a cloud-init template to the new VM by mounting the script as user-data.txt on a floppy.

Added cloud-init support for RHEV cloned images. RHEV template images should support cloud-init style customization via CloudForms customization templates, allowing the deployment and customization of VM images in RHEV without the need to the need to devise a custom solution. If a cloud-init customization template is associated with a RHEV clone provision request, the supplied customization template will be mounted as a floppy disk within the VM within the 'user-data.txt' file as required by cloud-init's RHEV datasource.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1049642">1049642</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>The physical volume for a direct mapped LUN was not being detected by the appliance, making the LVM data for the RHEVM storage inaccessible. This resulted in a VM fleecing failure. An evminit script now issues pvscan at boot to detect physical volumes, enabling the appliance to access storage data.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1049596">1049596</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Need for logging enhancements for automate rake task - The evm_automate.log change details are backwards as it details the difference between the currently loaded model and the default model. So if the user has added an Instance to their custom model, the log reports this as a deletion - which is counter intuitive. evm_automate.log describes new classes as new namespaces. The differences should be shown as changes to the default model.

Added granular import, modified rake tasks: Added import namespace and class, multi-domain import and export. Also changed new_domain_name to import_as to be consistent with export_as option. Added tests and contexts.
Changed replace = true/false to mode=add/replace/merge and changed rake tasks to use yaml import/export tasks, and removed xml based tasks.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1142231">1142231</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Previously, the IP addresses of all virtual machines in SCVMM were being gathered regardless of whether or not the virtual machine was running. This filled the evm.log with redundant error logging. Now, IP addresses are only collected for running virtual machines and the evm.log is not spammed with false errors.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1049593">1049593</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Need for a different file output for automate rake task -- The evm_automate.log format is useful to analysis, but difficult to work with when reporting to the customer as the log format makes that difficult.

Added granular import, modified rake tasks: Added import namespace and class, multi-domain import and export. Also changed new_domain_name to import_as to be consistent with export_as option. Added tests and contexts.
Changed replace = true/false to mode=add/replace/merge and changed rake tasks to use yaml import/export tasks, and removed xml based tasks.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1045202">1045202</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>This update allows a user to specify the amount of memory to reserve (memory guarantee in RHEV terms) for a given VM. Certain environments, such as non-production data centers have a requirement to overcommit VM memory utilization. By default, RHEV guarantees all requested memory for a VM, preventing the ability to overcommit memory. Hence, administrators were not able to overcommit memory for VMs. Administrators can now specify the amount of memory reserved for the VM.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1145306">1145306</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the beta version of CloudForms Management Engine 5.3, while updating the appliance from version 5.2.z to 5.3, the update start script did not stop the appliance correctly before starting the update. This bug was fixed by updating the update start script to stop the appliance correctly before starting the update.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1044777">1044777</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the previous version of CloudForms Management Engine, there was a navigation error in the set virtual machine / instance ownership page for virtual machines or instances related to a Red Hat OpenStack provider. The error resulted in displaying all virtual machines and instances in the CloudForms Management Engine database, instead of displaying only the virtual machines and instances related to the Red Hat OpenStack provider. This bug was fixed in the navigation code by directing the browser to go back to the calling page instead of going to the show all page, from the set virtual machine / instance ownership page. The correct list of virtual machines and instances is now shown after navigating away from the set virtual machine / instance ownership page.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1043213">1043213</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>A redundant "Set Retirement Date" button appeared for already retired virtual machines and instances. This fix removes the button for retired virtual machines and instances.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1043076">1043076</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>There was no way to export just the methods, export allowed you to export methods from the database, or from a specified xml export file.

Added extract_methods to automate rake task; Added the ability to extract methods from the database or xml file.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1043057">1043057</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Exporting nested namespaces required specifying the parent and the child namespace, instead of the expected action of exporting everything under a specified namespace. A code update fixes the namespace export to include child namespaces.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1043011">1043011</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Restore EVM Appliance Factory Configuration results in file system check error.

Restore EVM Appliance Factory Configuration option has been removed and replaced by configure database. Configure database handles disabling and enabling the pg daemon, configuring the /etc/fstab and much more, making Restore EVM Appliance Factory Configuration option now redundant.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1040698">1040698</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In case the database was not yet configured, using the 'Set Static Network Configuration option' explicitly restarted evmserverd, which did not work. As a result of this bug, using the 'Set Static Network Configuration option' from within the CFME console failed.
To fix this issue, the 'Set Static Network Configuration option' was fixed so it no longer restarts evmserverd. Additionally, the postgresql service was set so that it did not stop when cleaning logs and rebooting.
As a result of this fix, setting a static ip address configuration from within the CFME console works as expected.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1145794">1145794</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the beta version of CloudForms Management Engine 5.3, the database migration script could fail when upgrading from version 5.2.z to 5.3 on the master appliance, with an error about a missing group for the current user. This could happen if the record for the user's group was missing. This bug was fixed by deleting the user's current group information if the group's record was missing. The database migration script no longer fails if the current user's group information is not present.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1039310">1039310</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>The action_raise_automation_event method was raising a synthetic event without passing it the necessary object data. This caused control policies not to pass virtual machine information when sending data to automate. The action_raise_automation_event method has been updated to pass context data to the raise_synthetic_event method, and virtual machine information is now sent correctly to automate.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1081006">1081006</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>If no customization directory was specified while adding a new PXE server, the PXE provisioning did not complete.
This issue has been fixed in the latest version of CFME. PXE server can now be added without providing a customization directory.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1039157">1039157</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Running VM scans with a CFME 5.2.1.3 appliance failed against vSphere with a VDDK error. This was caused by an OpenSSL bug. The issue has been fixed in Red Hat Enterprise Linux 6.5 (BZ#1040069), and CFME scans now run correctly.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1081635">1081635</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>The Amazon Instance Type list available through the Cloud Forms Management Engine interface was out of sync with the options available through the Amazon EC2 console. This meant the user was unable to create instances of all types available on Amazon EC2. The list of Amazon instance types was updated, and all Amazon instance types are now available to the user in the Cloud Forms Management Engine interface.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1038819">1038819</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>An error in code designed to prevent constant reseeding by checking an mtime file caused feature seeding to fail. Additionally, MiqProductFeature.features was being cached, which caused problems when only seeding specific features. These issues caused some features to be missing from the UI. The check against the mtime file has been removed, and the cache is now cleared in EvmSpecHelper.clear_caches. All features now seed correctly and display as expected in the UI.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1038812">1038812</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Smart state analysis was logging excessive data. As a result, running a smart state analysis against a certain types of virtual machine completed successfully but no new data displayed under the VM summary and the proxy log contained several syntax errors. The analysis now logs only relevant scan data and information displays correctly under the VM summary.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1067527">1067527</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>This new enhancement allows CFME to capture OpenStack events from the RabbitMQ and Qpid messaging applications.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1082808">1082808</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Choosing one specific hour when creating a time profile with all days caused an undefined method error in the Host Capacity and Utilization screen:

Error: “undefined method 'nil_out_values' for &lt;MetricRollup:0x007faf671ca228&gt; [host/perf_chart_chooser]”.

The "apply_time_profile_hourly" method name has been updated to "nil_out_values_for_apply_time_profile", and the Capacity and Utilization screen now displays correctly.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1145831">1145831</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>While configuring the database from black console, accepting the default value of ‘1’ when prompted to create a new key resulted in an error:
"/opt/rh/ruby193/root/usr/share/ruby/optparse.rb:228:in 'quote': can't convert Fixnum to String (TypeError)".

Modified code for a better default option of generating a key. This has now resolved the issue and there is no error when creating encryption key.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1144483">1144483</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>The beta version of CloudForms Management Engine 5.3 carried a copy of documents from the 5.2 CloudForms Management Engine release. This was fixed by replacing the older documents with current documents from the CloudForms Management Engine 5.3.0 release. A CloudForms Management Engine 5.3 appliance now deploys with the documents for the correct release.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1146116">1146116</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>LDAP connection for all RestAPI web service calls failed for all users other than Admin.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1037652">1037652</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Migrations from EVM v4 to CloudForms 3.0 did not specify the new location for PostgreSQL logs and configuration. This stopped CloudForms Management Engine's UI from collecting the log files. This fix updates the log and configuration file locations. CloudForms 3.0 now uses the correct paths for log and configuration files.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1035638">1035638</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Clicking on Control -> Log, the UI threw an error: "Unexpected error encountered" Incompatible character encodings: ASCII-8Bit and UTF-8 [miq_policy/log]

Fixed code so that the VMDBLogger keeps the internal string encoding as UTF-8. This has now fixed the issue.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1035313">1035313</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In Clouds > Instances > Lifecycle > Provision Instances, selecting a template and clicking continue the provisioning tabs should be visible. On the 'Environment' tab, selecting the 'Choose Automatically' check box removes the 'Availability Zones', 'Security Groups' and 'Public IP Address' check box selections.

The dialogs have been updated to make the security group optional. Both OpenStack and Amazon don't require that the Security Group be provided explicitly for every provision request and if one isn't specified they use the Default Security group associated with the account, which has now resolved the issue.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1033900">1033900</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>The automation model was missing some of the model changes for service retirement. The components have been updated so that the /Automation/Servicelifecycle and /Factory/Statemachine/serviceretirement classes are now visible.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1030690">1030690</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the previous version of CloudForms Management Engine, changing the cloud provider quadrants setting in My Settings -> Visual had no effect. This bug was fixed by correcting the code that handled the cloud provider quadrants setting. The cloud provider quadrants now work as expected.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1030647">1030647</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the beta version of CloudForms Management Engine 5.3, navigating from the cloud provider instances explorer screen to the services main menu brought the user back to the instances explorer instead of loading the last visited sub menu under the services main menu. This was due to incorrect links generated for the services main menu in the instances and images list views. This bug was fixed in the code by generating the correct links for the services menu. Navigating to the services main menu from the instances explorer now works as expected.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1030552">1030552</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In Infrastructure > Virtual Machines, selecting a VM with Event Logs data on the summary screen throws an error.

Fixed link to “Event Logs” on VM summary screen to not blow up, needed to set @explorer for VM records so show_item and show_details methods can replace_right_cell when in VM explorer.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1030539">1030539</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the previous version of CloudForms Management Engine, clicking on the reset button on the customization template edit screen resulted in an undefined local variable or method error. This was because of a typographical error in the method name called when the reset button was pressed. This bug was fixed by correcting the typographical error in the method name. The reset button now works as expected on the customization template edit screen.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1030165">1030165</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the previous version of CloudForms Management Engine, after adding a Red Hat OpenStack Provider, there was only one entry called "No Availability Zone" listed in the availability zones tab. This was due to a bug in the API used to connect to the OpenStack provider. This bug was fixed by re-basing the library providing the OpenStack connection API to the newest version. The availability zones tab now list all availability zones as expected.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1083780">1083780</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the beta version of CloudForms Management Engine 5.3, while updating the appliance from version 5.2.z to 5.3, the update start script did not stop the appliance correctly before starting the update. This bug was fixed by updating the update start script to stop the appliance correctly before starting the update.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1111659">1111659</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Attempting to add or edit a service catalog item custom button resulted in "The user is not authorized for this task or item."

To fix this issue the RBAC check function was modified so that the user is allowed access to the service catalog item custom button, and is now able to add or edit the items.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1029204">1029204</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the beta version of CloudForms Management Engine 5.3,  Virtual Private Cloud and Cloud Subnet support to Amazon instance provisioning was not provided. To fix this issue, Virtual Private Cloud and Cloud Subnet fields were added to Amazon provisioning dialog. Additionally, existing fields (Security Groups/Elastic IP Address) from the Properties tab were moved to the Environment tab. The current version of CFME provided Virtual Private Cloud and Cloud Subnet support to Amazon instance provisioning.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1029152">1029152</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>The RHEV-M event monitor attempts to call a private class method when monitoring events. This causes a stack trace and event collection to fail. The call has been fixed, and the RHEV-M event monitor now collects events correctly.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1085939">1085939</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the beta version of CloudForms Management Engine 5.3, when editing Automate schema, changing a schema field for a class would change the value of the substitute column to true if it was false before. This was due to an error in the user interface programming logic. This bug was fixed by correcting the order in which the validation code converted boolean values. The substitute column no longer reverts to true when editing a class in Automate schema.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1027377">1027377</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the beta version of CloudForms Management Engine 5.3, users were getting an undefined method error when trying to save changes to an ISO Image. This issue was fixed by setting refresh_tree parameters. Now, users don't encounter any errors when trying to save ISO image type edit changes.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1055595">1055595</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Previously, Amazon provisioning failed  with the error "The security group 'xxxx' does not exist in VPC 'vpc-xxx" when 2 virtual private cloud networks have a security group with the same name. This was caused by using the CloudForms' security group configuration instead of Amazon's security group configuration. This has been fixed by changing code to pass the correct Amazon security_group IDs.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1026499">1026499</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>CFME migration documentation had no directions for customers attempting to migrate from EVM V4 to CFME 3.0 with respect to how to correctly handle dialogs that are saved into the filesystem in the EVM V4 environment, but incorporated into the VMDB in the CFME environments.

Added migration and tools script to import v4 provision dialogs stored in db/fixtures into the database.

https://access.redhat.com/site/articles/871253
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1086832">1086832</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Deprecated role logic cased an undefined method error:

[NoMethodError]: undefined method 'name' for nil:NilClass  Method:[rescue in block in seed]
/var/www/miq/vmdb/app/models/user.rb:744:in 'block (2 levels) in seed_users_to_group'

The old logic has been removed from the seed_users_to_group method, and the method now executes correctly.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1059834">1059834</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Customer requires the need to organize related services for PaaS provisioning -  They plan to utilize a parent service as the placeholder for environment and application name, with child services representing each application tier (i.e. EWS tier 1 server, EAP tier 2 service, etc). The VMDB database already has support for service hierarchies, but it is not currently exposed via the UI.

Added support for service hierarchies. For multipart service deployments, parent/child relationships between services can now be visualized in the 'My Services' tree view. The visibility of child services can be enabled via the "display" attribute on MiqAeServiceService for child services to appear in the hierarchy, by default they are hidden. Also added an explicit method for creating new service records via automation.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1025910">1025910</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the previous version of CloudForms Management Engine, the service dialog text area input was limited to 250 characters which is too small for several customer use cases, such as, lengthy URLs and SSH keys,
This issue is fixed in the current version of CFME. Now, the service dialog text area does not have a 250 character limit anymore.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1087495">1087495</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the previous version of CloudForms Management Engine, the user got a HTTP-403 forbidden error when trying to add, reset or remove a dashboard widget using Internet Explorer 8. This bug was fixed by correcting the handling of Internet Explorer 8 browser requests in the dashboard controller code. Users can now manipulate dashboard widgets when using Internet Explorer 8 as expected.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1061420">1061420</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Previously, the VmdbDatabase.seed module failed with a fatal undefined method error caused by an incorrect path to the Postgres data directory wherein paths to the postgres data directory were previously pointing to the old postgres location. All paths have been updated to prevent the fatal crash from happening.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1087539">1087539</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the beta version of CloudForms Management Engine 5.3, it was not possible to download the entire AE log file from the Automate -> Log section using the Internet Explorer 8 browser. This was caused by Internet Explorer not passing referer information on redirects to the CloudForms Management Engine appliance. This bug was fixed by whitelisting the known instances of this Internet Explorer error. It is now possible to download the entire AE log file using Internet Explorer.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1024837">1024837</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>The CatalogBundleInitialization method did not consistently set the options_hash key, which caused :option_0_db_name to pass unchanged to child tasks. The key has been updated to "option_key" to match the intended behaviour and log messages, and the correct :db_name is passed to child tasks.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1024019">1024019</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Dynamic dialog control did not pass field values when refresh button was clicked.

Code has been fixed and all dialog values are correctly passed; the issue is now resolved.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1087923">1087923</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>The Prince license file was not being applied properly, causing a lack of styling and a watermark to appear. The file has been updated with new contents for Prince version 9 and moved to the system directory for deployment on new appliances. Files now appear correctly.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1061945">1061945</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Automate methods did not correctly parse dialog values prefixed with "dialog_", which caused tags and options not to be passed to children. The regular expressions for automate methods have been updated to include the prefix, and dialog information is collected and passed correctly.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1088015">1088015</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Attempting to set/change database region of a CFME appliance from the black console fails with this error: undefined method 'bail_if_db_connections'(NoMethodError)
Updated code to add sass gem to Gemfile which has now fixed the issue.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1088205">1088205</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>If a user only had access to features in the PXE explorer, the main Infrastructure tab returned error. The user got a Missing template dashboard/maintab error when trying to access the infrastructure tab.
This was fixed by adding the PXE explorer to the list of features under the infrastructure tab.
Now, no error is reported when the user clicks on Infrastructure main tab.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1089061">1089061</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>The VM Analysis state machine creates a db transaction which blocked event-driven automate actions from running.  Actions include "VM Analysis Start", "VM Analysis Complete" and "VM Analysis Failure". Logs contained an error message like: "Automate: Unable to launch Automate Method because currently in SQL transaction"
Implemented internal state machine with no transaction required. This has now resolved the issue.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1021717">1021717</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the CloudForms Management Engine user interface if a user selected multiple services from the Services Explorer tab, he was not able to configure/set ownership or group options. This issue was fixed by applying code changes to set proper value when changing ownership for more than one service. Users can now set ownership and group for multiple services.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1090528">1090528</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>There was an error when performing smart analysis on a RHEV environment after a reboot.
Error message: 'Unable to mount filesystem'

The situation arose in a VM in the environment, when an unpartitioned virtual disk was added to a volume group of the VM, the unpartitioned virtual disk appeared as a logical volume (LV) in the volume group on the storage LUN. When the cfme appliance scans for physical volumes (PV), it sees the LV as a PV because of the metadata it finds on the LV. However, this isn't a problem when the virtual disk is partitioned because the metadata won't appear in the expected location on the LV.

Updated code so that CFME ignores physical volumes that are also logical volumes.  When determining which physical volumes correspond to RHEV storage LUNs, CFME will not consider physical volumes that are also logical volumes. This has fixed the issue and there is no error reported.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1021650">1021650</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the previous version of CloudForms Management Engine, the reports editor under the reports explorer had a incorrectly formatted "Selected" column on the Summary tab. This was caused by incorrect formatting of the table cell used to hold the "Selected" column. Additionally, the column name for the total count row in a saved report was incorrectly formatted. This was caused by incorrect processing of the column name. These bugs were fixed by correcting the formatting bugs for these form objects. The reports editor is formatted correctly in the current version of CloudForms Management Engine.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1090877">1090877</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Logged in user with super_administer role can be deleted via configuration with an error thrown: undefined method 'miq_user_role' for nil:NilClass [ops/x_button]
Appliance UI has been updated to check that both admin as well as the currently logged in user as per the UI session are restricted in that they cannot be deleted. New UI flash message added for "Current User %{name} cannot be deleted"
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1020337">1020337</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>IPMI credentials could not be deleted from a host's database. If they were removed and the host was saved, the IPMI credentials were not actually removed from the DB. They reappeared while editing the host. The code that excludes authentication records to be saved to the DB if userid is blank has been removed. The IPMI credentials are now permanently removed when deleted from the host's edit page.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1138861">1138861</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Previously, transferring an encryption key from one appliance to another appliance required a shell script. Now, the option to fetch a key from a remote machine appears in the appliance console.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1091104">1091104</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the beta version of CloudForms Management Engine 5.3, editing Zones under Configurations -> Settings resulted in an unauthorized user error message. Additionally, attempting to delete a Zone resulted in an invalid button action error. This was due to missing code to handle Zone edits and deletes. This bug was fixed by adding the code required to handle edits and deletes. Editing and deleting zones now works as expected.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1138478">1138478</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the beta version of CloudForms Management Engine 5.3, logrotate failed to rotate the VMDB log files with the message that the log file did not need rotating. This bug was fixed in the new version of CloudForms Management Engine 5.3.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1144065">1144065</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Previously, a typo in the assert_privileges call meant that users were experiencing authorization issues when attempting to edit a SmartProxy. This typo has been corrected and users can now edit a SmartProxy as expected.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1019443">1019443</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>The proxy password was exposed at Red Hat Update. When entering a proxy setup for Red Hat Updates, the proxy server's password was exposed in the /var/www/miq/vmdb/log/evm.log. The fix encrypts the passwords before putting options on the queue. As a result, the proxy password is no longer exposed in the log.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1092381">1092381</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the beta version of CloudForms Management Engine 5.3, creating a group with a duplicate name resulted in two instances of a flash message informing the administrator that the group name was already present. This was because the group name was being validated in two places in the code. This bug was fixed by removing one of the two group name validation code blocks. Only one flash message is now presented to the administrator when attempting to create a group with a duplicate name.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1136941">1136941</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the beta version of CloudForms Management Engine 5.3, a minor version update started from the web user interface would fail sometimes, without logging any errors in the evm log file. This was because the correct options were not passed to the yum update command. This bug was fixed by passing the correct options to the yum command. Additional log messages were added to raise errors about missing arguments for the yum command.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1136573">1136573</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the beta version of CloudForms Management Engine 5.3, when initializing the appliance with the appliance_console command, a very cryptic error was logged if a custom encryption key was not present and had to either be generated anew or copied over from an existing appliance. This bug was fixed by changing the appliance_console command to log a descriptive error if the encryption key was not found. The user can now correctly setup the encryption key for the appliance when running the appliance_console command.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1071440">1071440</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Due to an error in the Openstack Event Monitoring logic, calls to the Event Monitor resulted in a nil value instead of cache hits. This fix corrects the code logic and the OpenStack Event Monitor now returns cache hits.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1135072">1135072</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Appliance in the reporting region that performed power operations across regions had stopped working.

The region to region communication has been fixed:
    - vmdbws controller accepts username/password
    - the password is unique per installation due to encryption w/ v2_key
The above change has now fixed the problem.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1120364">1120364</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>CloudForms did not recover from temporary connection problems to external database: Stopping the external database for some time and restarting it, all CloudForms background processes except for MiqServer.monitor froze, and evm.log showed that MiqServer.monitor always failed an error message.
Code has been fixed in ruby193-rubygem-activerecord-3.2.17-4.el6cf and the issue has now been resolved.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1018392">1018392</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Searching for a VM name containing a dot (.) caused a database error: Database statement error encountered [vm_infra/x_search_by_name]. An SQL query issue with Rails 3.2.13 has been fixed. Searches can now be conducted for a VM name containing a dot (.) without causing an error.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1120412">1120412</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Migrating roles to group settings during the upgrade from EVM V4 to the current Cloud Forms Management Engine codebase used to fail with the error - undefined method 'settings' for nil:NilClass. This was because the migration code could not handle groups with a nil miq_user_role. This was fixed by making the migration code aware of such groups. The migration process now completes successfully with this fix.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1135052">1135052</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>For 5.3 updates to work, the RHSCL repository "rhel-server-rhscl-6-rpms" was required to be enabled after CFME has successfully registered and subscribed. However, RHSCL repository should be auto-enabled once subscribed.

Code was updated to add SCL channel when registering. Also, migrated Default Registration Channel Names for v5.3.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1135051">1135051</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>When configuring ipa using the appliance_console, the server defaults the ipa realm based upon the host's domain name. But the machines in the lab require a different realm -- The ipa can not be installed without this change.

Code was fixed and the ipa configuration installation is now successful.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1063476">1063476</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>A policy configured to recognize an increase in the virtual machine's RAM size, failed to report on the event when the RAM size increased. The logs indicated that the prior size and the current size were reversed in the condition logic. VM_drift_state refactoring reversed the order in which the drift states were returned causing the compare method to return the opposite result. The compare method's condition logic has been fixed to recognize the correct values. RAM size comparison should now be correctly recognized in CFME 5.2.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1014799">1014799</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>The directory containing postgresql 'psql' command was not in the default path, therefore the backup and restore processing was not possible.

Prepended the library path to the worker command line, re-enabled the source of defaults file to setup user environment. This has fixed the issue and the psql command is available on the appliance.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1006637">1006637</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>CloudForms Management Engine did not capture the number of cores available on the host's CPUs. This resulted in CloudForms Management Engine reporting fewer host CPU's then what was actually on the host system.
To fix this issue the code querying the RHEVm API was corrected to include Host CPU attributes in the query.
The host CPU information is now correctly displayed in host summary and the host hardware information report. It also adds up correctly in the provider summary.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1132893">1132893</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>When restored a 3.0 Database that had multiple connections to various provider, was unable to edit the password field of the providers. Click on the provider, selecting configuration and edit, the UI crashed with an error.

Not shipping the default v2_key on the cfme appliance. Added key generation to the appliance console. The changes have now resolved the issue.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1094487">1094487</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In Configure -> Configuration -> Access control, user role can be deleted while a new group is assigned the role. And clicking on the group after deleting the role the UI will crash.  Also if a user is based on the group the login screen will fail.
User role should not be deleted while a group is still assigned. Added :dependent => :restrict to MiqUserRole's miq_groups association which has now resolved the issue. Error message while deleting a role with a group assigned: Role "test-role": Error during 'destroy': Cannot delete record because of dependent miq_groups
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1114163">1114163</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>As part of the RHCI Common Install, we would like the ability to query, modify and/or make a API call to the CFME black console menu options for remote appliance configuration. Also the ability to attach and configure the VMDB database on the deployed appliance.

CloudForms Management Engine 5.3 includes appliance_console_cli which lets you setup a local database, or external database. It also partitions the database disk.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1004039">1004039</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Previously, duplicate entries of utilization records were displayed when viewing the virtual machine's hourly performance chart report data. When metric_rollups tables were created, previous tables, including the hourly data table were merged into one, resulting in the daily record for the chosen day being returned along with the hourly records. An interval type was added to the "where" clause to fix this issue. Only one record should now appear in the virtual machine's hourly performance chart report.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1001029">1001029</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Restore EVM Appliance Factory Configuration results in file system check error.

Restore EVM Appliance Factory Configuration option has been removed and replaced by configure database. Configure database handles disabling and enabling the pg daemon, configuring the /etc/fstab and much more, making Restore EVM Appliance Factory Configuration option now redundant.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1094984">1094984</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Customer chooses to change the default password for their POSTGRESQL database retaining the ‘root’ user id. When a newly created appliance attempts to join the existing VMDB after the default root password has changed, the attempt fails returning ‘Validated - failed with error - FATAL password authentication failed for user "root". This occurred in the situation where the root userid is retained but the password is altered.

Added fix_auth tool to upgrade user to a new encryption key which has now fixed the issue.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1143307">1143307</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Previously, an inconsistency in Gemfiles between versions meant that an update to 5.3.0.10 was prevented by a locked RubyGem. Now, the Gemfile.lock has been updated so that updates operate as expected.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1069746">1069746</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Selecting a snapshot in the snapshots tree did not refresh the toolbars. Hence, the 'Create snapshot' button which should only be enabled when an active snapshot is selected, was enabled for inactive snapshots as well. The code to replace center toolbars when a snapshot is selected has been fixed and the 'Create snapshot' button is no longer enabled for inactive snapshots.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1064448">1064448</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>This fix corrects an error in the name of the appliance template users download from the Red Hat Customer Portal.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1064933">1064933</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>An automated script referencing an OpenStack instance provisioned by CFME failed with the error "uninitialized constant MiqAeMethodService::MiqAeServiceMiqProvisionOpenstack" because  the MiqAeServiceMiqProvisionOpenstack method was missing from the automated service models. This missing provisioning service model has since been added into the automated service models. The script now runs successfully.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=989625">989625</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>purge_all_storage_data.rb tool failed in CFME 5.2

A FFI version of the vddk binding was implemented and the issue that the message not being able to load the C vddk binding doesn't appear any more.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1102287">1102287</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the beta version of CloudForms Management Engine 5.3, the default "Repository Name" field in the Red Hat Updates section referred to the CFME 5.2 repository. This has been corrected to refer to the CFME 5.3 repository name, which is "cf-me-5.3-for-rhel-6-rpms".
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1122123">1122123</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>The provision task had a state named "provisioned" which was
not a valid state for its associated provision request. As a result, after a provision task had finished provisioning a VM, the task's status could not be sent to its parent provision request due to a validation error. The "provisioned" state is now recognized as a valid state, which allows the task's status to reflect correctly.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1101819">1101819</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the beta version of CloudForms Management Engine 5.3, configuring an email alert for a policy assigned to a Virtual Machine did not work as expected. This was due to incorrect handling of the recipient email address in the alert processing code. This bug was resolved by correcting the handling of the recipient email address. Email alerts for policies now work as expected.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1131716">1131716</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the older versions of Cloud Forms Management Engine, the VMDB configuration parser did not catch syntax errors in the configuration file that were a result of the administrator using the Advanced configuration editor. This resulted in a fatal error later. This was fixed by catching syntax error exceptions in the configuration parser. The UI now displays a user friendly warning about the invalid syntax using a flash message.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1131692">1131692</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>When enabling external authentication with an IPA Server, while the Web-UI allowed for username/passwords of the IPA server to be specified to login, the REST API as well as the SOAP Web Services did not and resulted in a 401 error. Only the local admin account was allowed in.

Updated REST and SOAP API's to support external authentication and the issue is now resolved.
    - Added a :require_user option to User.authenticate
    - Added :timeout option to MiqTask.wait_for_taskid
    - Updated REST API to pass HTTP Env and option to User.authenticate
    - Updated Appliance Console to extend the Apache External configuration
    to be REST and SOAP API aware.
    - Properly unconfiguring HTTPD application from appliance console.
    - Added REST API and SOAP :authentication_timeout config, both
    default to 30 seconds
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1122259">1122259</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>RHEV VMs with custom attributes longer than 255 characters prevented the affected VMs from being updated and also prevented deleted RHEV VMs from being being flagged as deleted in the VMDB, as this violated the database schema. The RHEV inventory parser was updated to truncate custom attribute values that exceed the DB limit to the expected size, which allowed the VMs to be updated.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1122264">1122264</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>vSphere fleecing was not working due to missing symlinks in the /var/www/miq/lib/VixDiskLib/vddklib.
Fixed VMware fleecing Issue with missing Symlinks:
Changed VixDiskLibServer process LD_LIBRARY_PATH to use the actual location of the VixDiskLib libraries.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1065126">1065126</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>If a VM had more than one disk whose name did not match an expected pattern, the disks would overwrite each other within the database, resulting in an incorrect disk inventory for the VM. The RHEV inventory refresher unit test needed to be updated in support of the new VM disk location assignment logic. Now all disks are assigned a unique controller location to prevent unexpected overwrites.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1131159">1131159</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Cloud Form Management Engine 5.3.0 builds were not being built from the correct Red Hat Enterprise Linux z stream, making the appliance require hundreds of updates on an initial yum update. This issue is fixed in the latest version.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=980065">980065</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>During virtual machine analysis, since the scan code is unaware of the profile to use, all items such as files, registry entries, etc (depending on the VM OS) in the custom analysis profile are ignored and are not imported. While, all items in the "default" analysis profile are captured as expected.

Code has been updated and the user is able to assign custom analysis profile to VM. The custom analysis profile is now read and passed on correctly. However, the data collected from the custom profile are not saved, thus the results are not shown on UI.  A new bug 1114063 has been created to address the problem.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1130310">1130310</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Fog threw a ServiceNotAvailable error when attempting to connect to an Openstack service that is not available.  However with Swift, Fog produced an unexpected error if Swift is unavailable. In the case of Fog, the problem is that it expects the "openstack-service-type" to be an array.  For Swift, the "openstack-service-type" is the string "object-store".  This causes a problem when attempting to build a message indicating that the service is unavailable.

Updated a patch that works around this bug in Fog where, if Swift is unavailable, Fog will now throw an unexpected error instead of indicating that the service is unavailable. This patch will suffice until an updated patch is included in Fog, with an update to the latest community version.

Also, note that if Swift is misconfigured, attempts to manage the environment by CFME may fail with a 503 error.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1067202">1067202</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Need for allowing widget contents to be saved based on either Group/TZ combination or User/Group combination (for members of self service groups)
* Change the UI to lookup widget contents based on User/Group combination first, then Group/TZ
* Modifying the logic to fetch widget contents to the model layer, so UI code can just ask for the contents of a widget
* If a User no longer belongs to an LDAP group, remove his dashboards for that group so widgets are no longer generated for it
Code has been updated to include the following changes:

*Generate the widget contents based on group/TZ combination
	-instead of per user for non-self service users.
Replace owner_id and owner_type with miq_group_id and userid in table miq_widget_content.
	-Remove all MiqWidgetContent data when migrating.
	-When owner is a user, there is no information about the user's group to migrate to.
	-MiqWidgetContent will be created based on either a group/TZ or group/user combination.

*Enabled creation of a widget content for each of a self service user's multiple groups.
*Pass both group and user objects to MiqWidget#generate_report to support multiple groups.
*Updated the specs related with widget generation.
*Added the checking of user filters at MiqGroup level to Rbac.get_user_info.
	-The user filters should be checked against the specified MiqGroup first to support multiple groups.
	-Check the user filters from user.miq_group only when no Miqgroup is specified for the user.
*Delete the widget contents with user_id = nil
	-when a group is changed to be a self service group.
*Spec changes for the case when a group is changed to be a self service group.
*Add/remove the index on table miq_widget_contents.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1067541">1067541</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Previously, the OpenStack event monitor would test each event monitor plugin repeatedly to determine the best plugin for each EMS. This enhancement allows OpenStack event monitor to cache the determined best plugin for each EMS the first time it has been tested.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1130286">1130286</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Now that the cloud quota is shown during cloud instance provisioning, Amazon provisioning broke and threw an error.

The tenant column on pre_prov partial has been fixed. In cases where both Amazon and Openstack images are available in the "Select and Image" table in the _pre_prov partial, the table shows up with uneven rows. This is caused by Amazon not having tenants whereas OpenStack does have tenants. Originally, the logic for showing the table column header would arbitrarily include the header based solely on the first template in the list to be shown. Now, the column header is shown if any of the templates in the list can show a cloud tenant. Also, the logic for showing the table cell is based on whether the table tenants header is shown. Additionally, the logic for showing the data inside the table cell is based on whether the template in the current column can respond_to the 'cloud_tenant' method. These changes have now fixed the problem.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=956833">956833</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>When integrating with Red Hat IDM, an LDAP protocol error was thrown because of the ruby net-ldap gem bug.

Upgrade net-ldap for fix for LDAP Controls:
	-Upgraded net-ldap version is now installed – ruby193-rubygem-net-ldap-0.7.0-1.el6cf.noarch and the issue is now resolved.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1100921">1100921</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Need an alias for /var/www/miq/vmdb

Alias has been added, vmdb='cd /var/www/miq/vmdb'
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1128291">1128291</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>After installing two 5.3.0.2 appliances, configuring one to use an internal DB, and configuring the other to connect to the database on the first, and entering the default credentials for the external DB, resulted in an error message: FATAL: password authentication failed for user "root". This was because the socket on localhost that uses ident was not properly identifying the root user. Also, the wrong password was ending up in the database, that is "md5#{md5("root")}" - which can not be accessible.

Setup password for internal database config that enabled connection to an external database successfully and the issue is now resolved.
    - both internal and external prompt for user credentials
    - move database config into common area
    - don’t show (none for non default) if no default password
    - use md5 for all network connections (no ident installed)
    - allow cli to pass in username/password
    - configure CentOS appliance with default password
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1127959">1127959</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>This update fixes an issue where the Openstack Event Catcher prevented the amqp_port value from the config/vmdb.tmpl.yml file from taking effect. Additionally, the default value in the config/vmdb.tmpl.yml file was set to assume SSL for AMQP. Assuming SSL for AMQP proved confusing since several other steps are required to actually configure the appliance to support AMQP over SSL. The default port setting for AMQP has been changed to non-ssl and the def_options has been changed so that the default values are only used when there are no corresponding values provided in the options parameter. This means that the amqp_port value from the config/vmdb.tmpl.yml file will now be able to take effect.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1127789">1127789</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>After deploying a 5.2.z appliance, configure the database, and then log into the UI and enabling the smartproxy server role, the web UI worker seems to crash (abort) with a stack trace and restarts.
“undefined method 'error_field' for nil:NilClass”
Fixed code such that the undefined method 'error_field' for nil:NilClass is not logged in evm.log and that the Web UI stays online after enabling smartproxy server role. This has now fixed the issue.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1126476">1126476</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>SmartState Analysis failed for non-English Windows versions with an error message:
invalid byte sequence in UTF-8 for VM: /rhev/data-center/c14cb2e6-3c7a-443e-8ddd-0d31e5493d86/mastersd/master/vms/5245326d-db6a-415e-b101-89cf82467117/5245326d-db6a-415e-b101-89cf82467117.ovf]

Fixed SmartState Analysis failures on non-English VMs. Text retrieved from non-English Windows VMs may be encoded in UTF-16. This text may contain byte sequences that are not valid in UTF-8. Check the text for valid encoding, and convert to UTF-8 as needed. These changes have now fixed the issue.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1099609">1099609</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>When selecting a VM to edit from the host summary screen, the user is presented with two VM lists to select from.
The form used to select a VM to edit was confusing.
To fix this issue, the VM selection form was fixed to only populate the list of VMs on the right hand side and the list on the left hand was left blank.
As a result of this fix, only one list of VMs is now presented to the user.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1099622">1099622</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Provisioning an Amazon instance threw an error : undefined method 'get_timezones' for &lt;MiqProvisionAmazonWorkflow:0x0000000b6b6e48&gt; [vm_cloud/pre_prov]. This issue was caused by an issue on build miq-01-0516 where the automate domains were not properly seeded.

The issue with the build where the Automate model was not seeded properly has been fixed, and all the Automate Namespaces in Automate Explorer are available. Provisioning an Amazon instance is now successful without any error.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=946836">946836</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>When the EMS Events generated from RHEV that CloudForms Management Engine (CFME) does not know about, CFME would log an error to evm.log. The fix:
1) Identified the specific RHEV events that were causing failures and create event mappings in CFME.  This fix would stop CFME from logging errors for those specific RHEV events.
2) Created better mechanism for identifying future unmapped RHEV events.  After this fix, CFME will log a warning containing details of the unmappeed event to the rhevm.log file.  This data can be collected easier from the rhevm.log since that log file does not receive nearly the traffic that evm.log receives.
As a result, CFME no longer logs an incorrect error.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1099996">1099996</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Creating a catalog item of type “RHEV” resulted in an error: undefined method 'get_timezones' for &lt;MiqProvisionRedhatWorkflow:0x0000000c157ed8&gt; [catalog/atomic_form_field_changed]. This issue was caused by an issue on build miq-01-0516 where the automate domains were not properly seeded.

Code fixed: Added missing routes when adding Catalog Item Type – Redhat. The issue is now resolved as there is no error displayed while adding a catalog item of type REDHAT.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1098627">1098627</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>When editing ownership of VMs or Templates as sub lists from any parents listnav was displayed on the left, instead of showing a blank screen. Also, when trying to edit ownership on Templates for a host, it threw as error about missing partial.

Fixed code to not show listnav when on Set ownership form for list of VMs or Templates for another CI. Also fixed the partial name when pressing Set Ownership button for list of Templates for another CI through relationships. Fixed code to display "Save/Reset" buttons on ownership screen. When editing ownership of VMs or Templates as sub lists from any parents it now displays blank listnav on the left side.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
		</variablelist>
		<variablelist>
			<title>Automate</title>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1119402">1119402</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Previously, a routing error occurred when provisioning cloud instances:

Action not implemented [vm_cloud/pre_prov]

Now, this issue has been fixed, and the error no longer occurs.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1102852">1102852</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>When attempting to use the Integration / VimApi / VMware_HotAdd_Disk method to add a disk to a VM in VMware, a ruby error was generated and disk wasn’t being added.

The MiqVimVm#addDisk method was using the public accessor dsName2mo() when creating the ConfigSpec used to add a disk to the VM; causing the returned object to be wrapped in a MiqDrbReturn object. This caused the MiqDrbReturn object to be passed back to the client, since only top-level return objects should be wrapped in MiqDrbReturn. The client would then pass this unexpected object to the VMware VIM API, causing the failure.

Using the internal accessor dsName2mo_local() when acquiring sub-objects of the ConfigSpec, since this method does not wrap its returned value in a MiqDrbReturn object was the solution.

Also, fixed VMware service model methods for set_memory and add_disk; both method names were incorrectly set to an existing method name in a previous refactoring. This has fixed the issue and disk is  now being added to a VM in Vmware without any error.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1109256">1109256</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the beta version of CloudForms Management Engine UI, when a user tried to edit ISO image in Infra / PXE / ISO Datastores, an "Action not implemented [pxe/x_button]" error page was displayed, which resulted in failure to edit. This issue was fixed by adding the missing routing information in the code. In the current version, the user can edit an ISO image successfully.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1114747">1114747</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Attempting to create an instance in automate, threw an error: WARN -- : Session::DalliStore#set: Value too large, memcached can only store 1048576 bytes per key [key: MIQ:VMDB:86346c9e21029126785058ecd92202e6, size: 1126745].

Changed code to add/edit instance to not store AR Objects in @edit, but, to store the required fields into array of hashes instead. Besides, some minor cleanups were also made to methods. These changes has fixed the issue and now there is no error.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1128891">1128891</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>This update fixes an issue where the VM configuration maximum limit could not be modified. This meant that the Reconfigure VM Option in Cloudforms would throw an error if a value higher than 16GB Memory or 8 processors is entered. The configuration maximums for VMware 5.1 is 1TB and 64 vCPU. The memory limit in Cloudforms has been adjusted to the VMware hardware version limit. This means that the Reconfigure VM Option in Cloudforms will no longer throw an error if a value higher than 16GB Memory or 8 processors is entered.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1146508">1146508</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Adding a domain with a space in its name, a flash message with success message appeared but the domain could not be seen in the UI.

coding style: Add space after comma. Also updated code to show error message when a domain/namespace already exists. Previously, webui would display a success message informing the domain/namespace was successfuly created, although it wasn't. The changes have now fixed the problem.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1133707">1133707</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>When a user attempted to reconfigure a VM (memory or CPU) the settings did not go through to make that change in VMWare. The related events were visible in the evm.log but there were no tasks being done in the Vcenter.

The Reconfigure VM action creates a request which is not auto-approved with the default automate model. A user or admin must go to Services -> Request and approve the corresponding VM Reconfigure request. Other actions, like VM/Service/Host provision, send the UI to the Service -> Request screen once the action is successfully submitted.

Fixed code to redirect to the Requests list page after a VM Reconfigure. This has now fixed the problem.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1135070">1135070</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>The update_retirement_status method in automate did not return a status. The method has been updated and now returns a status as expected.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1132139">1132139</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the Cloud Forms Management Engine 5.3 beta release, the RedHat Automate data store domain was not enabled on the appliance. This was because the MiqAeDatastore seeding process did not honor the enabled flag for the RedHat domain. This was fixed by changing the data store code to recognize the enabled flag during seeding. The RedHat Automate data store is correctly enabled as expected now.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1132142">1132142</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the older version of Cloud Forms Management Engine, a class not found error is encountered when running a simulation for the Request object under Automate and the simulation fails. This was due to an extra round of URL encoding being run on the class URL resulting in a mangled URL. This was fixed by disabling the additional encoding pass. Request object simulations can now be submitted successfully.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1133672">1133672</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Placement of cloud instances is currently not implemented as part of the Automate State Machine; it is hard coded to be executed at specific points during provisioning. Placement of cloud instances should be part of Automate State Machine as the user may like to call Placement logic after specific states.

Automate DB changes for Cloud Placement via State Machine. Also, Model and Dialog Changes for Placement via State Machine. This has the now fixed the problem, both types of placement: "Choose Automatically" and "Configure placement" is correct.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1132136">1132136</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the older versions of Cloud Forms Management Engine, VM placement logic was embedded in the CFME internal state machine. This did not provide the flexibility that was required by some users who wanted to call the logic before or after pre-provisioning was run, or at some other specific point. This was fixed by implementing the VM placement logic as a part of the Automate State Machine. Note that the old logic of running placement via UI_PROVISION_INFO from the internal state machine will still work.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1135055">1135055</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>As part of the Method Override across domains a user can create just the method in their high priority domain. The user expects that their methods would get used instead of the method from a lower priority domain. The feature failed with the "method missing" message.

Code has been updated to implement case insensitive search of method names. When searching for methods, the case shouldn't be taken into account. This has now fixed the problem.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1135057">1135057</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In Lifecycle > Clone this VM, cloning a VM and not choosing a customization spec results in an error. Clone should complete, or a UI error should state that customization spec is required.

Basic provisioning functionality has changed since the manageIQ/RedHat automate domain split. The ManageIQ domain contains very basic provision functionality and the VMware preprovision_clone_to_vm automate method contains only a log message. The RedHat domain contains more advanced provisioning options and the VMware preprovision_clone_to_vm automate method contains the original automate method functionality. The RedHat domain automate method has been changed to comment out the customization spec section, leaving the code there to be used as a sample.

The issue has now been resolved.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1132115">1132115</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>A new finished statemachine state has been added which calls a common method to set the provision status to finished and sets the appropriate message.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1121287">1121287</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Previously, the host provisioning request would not complete when adding a vSphere host, and attempting to provision the host through CFME. As a result, the request would be approved, but the status would still show as "Pending."

Now, this issue has been fixed by updating the automate method parse_provider_category for host provisioning, and adding a check for miq_host_provision key. As a result,
this corrects the issue of host provisioning not being routed to the proper state machine.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1139868">1139868</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Attempting to use VimApi / VMware_HotAdd_CPU resulted in an MissingVMObject error.

Modifying the VMware_HotAdd_CPU script and created a button that does not use a dialog and the issue is now fixed.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1131591">1131591</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Relationships for cloud resources in the following service models were not exposed to other models:

MiqAeServiceAvailabilityZone
MiqAeServiceCloudNetwork
MiqAeServiceCloudSubnet
MiqAeServiceFlavor
MiqAeServiceFloatingIp
MiqAeServiceSecurityGroup

These relationships have now been exposed to other Automate models, and missing association flags were added.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1118831">1118831</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>When provisioning a VM instance with VmProvisionRequest an error was raised. This was caused by an authentication error in the vmdbws controller.

The basic authentication logic is fixed in the vmdbws controller, ensuring the error lo longer appears.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1139870">1139870</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>The Virtualization Type field (HVM or paravirtual) was missing for Amazon images in the cloud provider view. The UI has been updated, and these fields now display correctly.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1139881">1139881</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Amazon images have a property called root_device_type that is either instance_store or EBS. There are instance types, for example t1.micro, that only support EBS. Attempting to deploy an instance_store image to an EBS only instance causes an error, for example:

[AWS::EC2::Errors::UnsupportedOperation]: AMI 'ami-edaa1f84' with an instance-store root device is not supported for the instance type 't1.micro'.

The CFME web console has been updated to filter based on instance type so only those relevant to a selected datastore are displayed.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1105113">1105113</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>The Rake import evm:automate:import always resulted in a Read-Only Domain.

Changes were made to Import/Export to allow for setting of ENABLE/SYSTEM:

    1. ManageIQ domain will be automatically set to
    SYSTEM=true,ENABLED=true,PRIORITY=0
    2. Support for restore, during restore the ENABLED attribute from domain
    yaml file will be honored.
    3. PRIORITY will never be honored from the domain yaml file, it is only
    used to set the import order when doing a multi domain import
    4. By default for single domain imports the domain will be created as
    disabled (ENABLED=false).
    5. ManageIQ domain will be called ManageIQ even if IMPORT_AS=manageiq
    6. During restore create the $ namespace
    7. rake script allows for ENABLED=true|false
    8. rake script allows for SYSTEM=true|false

The above changes have now fixed the issue.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1140734">1140734</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>During OpenStack provisioning, the 'Cloud Network' field is now available only when there is more than one available cloud network. In cases where only one network is available, provisioning can be completed even if 'Cloud Network' is not populated or selected.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1141292">1141292</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Previously, the /system/policy/request_denied and request_pending instances had incorrect relationship values. Now, those instances have same value as request_approved and other instances in this class, and new /System/policy instances for each object type for _denied and _pending have been added.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1131535">1131535</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Statemachine method class schema have been updated to add vendor specific methods and relationships.  Vendor specific preprovision, postprovision and customize request methods have also been added.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1143046">1143046</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>During OpenStack provisioning, the selection of a tenant does not cause other fields to filter based on that selection. The web console has been updated to filter based on tenant or provider, as appropriate.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1106924">1106924</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>When the VirtualE1000e Network Interface Card (NIC) definition was introduced in VMWare Virtual Infrastructure Methodology (VIM) 5.0 release, Virtual Machines (VM) were not able to use the VirtualE1000e NIC.
To fix this issue the VirtualE1000e NIC definition was added to the VIM mapping registry.
VMs are now able to use the VirtualE1000e NIC successfully.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1145198">1145198</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Missing service models caused OpenStack quota data to be unavailable to the OpenStack provider and tenant in Automate. Service models for OpenstackResourceQuota have been created and the relationships between provider and tenant have been defined. OpenStack quota data is now exposed to Automate.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1124924">1124924</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>A retired VM cannot have its retirement date reset. This is by design in order to prevent the statemachine attempting to remove a VM that has been unretired by a user. This bug was closed as NOTABUG.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1123380">1123380</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Selecting the "Choose Automatically" option on the Environment tab during provisioning failed to find a suitable host for the request even though hosts were available. The eligible_resources method has been fixed to correctly update options during the creation workflow. Provisioning now automatically selects the least utilized host and storage.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1106524">1106524</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>The automate task and the sub-task for add_disk used the same task_id value in the miq_queue table.  This meant the queue items did not execute at the same time and did not complete as quickly as expected. This was fixed by passing a task_id of nil to the queue options for the add_disk task.  The automate add_disk task now completes in a timely fashion.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
		</variablelist>
		<variablelist>
			<title>Control</title>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1093588">1093588</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the beta version of CloudForms Management Engine 5.3, under the Control tab -> Explorer -> Alerts accordion, editing any alert to add an email id resulted in an undefined method error. This error was due to the incorrect handling of the email id string in the backend code. This bug was fixed by correcting the handling of the email id string. Email ids can now be added to alerts as expected.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1108541">1108541</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the previous version of CloudForms Management Engine, when listing the virtual machine's files, the file icon for log files was missing and the "image missing" message was displayed. A missing icon file error was also recorded in production.log file. This bug was fixed by adding the missing log icon file to the icons image directory. The correct icon is now displayed for the VM's log file.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1100827">1100827</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the beta version of CloudForms Management Engine 5.3, if a Virtual Machine compliance policy marked a VM as non-compliant when a condition evaluated to true, the VM was still incorrectly shown as compliant in the details pane. This bug was a result of a typographical error in the code that implemented policy compliance. This bug was fixed by correcting the typographical error. A VM is now correctly marked as non-compliant if a policy marks it as such.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1104814">1104814</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the beta version of CloudForms Management Engine 5.3, if a Virtual Machine compliance policy marked a VM as non-compliant when a condition evaluated to true, the VM was still incorrectly shown as compliant in the details pane. This bug was a result of a typographical error in the code that implemented policy compliance. This bug was fixed by correcting the typographical error. A VM is now correctly marked as non-compliant if a policy marks it as such.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1106456">1106456</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the beta version of CloudForms Management Engine 5.3, importing policy sets that attempted to be saved during import resulted in the error 'cannot call create unless the parent is saved'. This bug was due to an error in the code used to import files. This bug was fixed by correcting the error in the import file upload code. Users are now able to import policy sets as expected.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1097393">1097393</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In a RHEVM-CFME environment where IP addresses are assigned after an appliance is created and during the first boot-up, RHEVM emits the event ‘NETWORK_UPDATE_VM_INTERFACE’. The Event Handler Configuration file did not perform any special actions (eg ems refresh for source VM) for this event, resulting in the VMDB containing VM instances for newly provisioned appliances, but no IP address in the VMDB instance. Any post-provisioning activity dependent on that IP address existing in the VMDB had a high probability of failing until the next full provider refresh completed correcting the situation.

Added event network update vm interface for rhev/ovirt post functions
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1093739">1093739</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>This enhancement adds support for OpenLDAP authentication.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1114063">1114063</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>During virtual machine analysis, since the scan code is unaware of the profile to use, all items such as files, registry entries, etc (depending on the VM OS) in the custom analysis profile are ignored and are not imported. Moreover, the data collected from the custom profile is not saved, thus the results are not shown in the UI. A code update enables the user to assign custom analysis profile to VM and the custom profile is saved. The custom analysis profile is now read, passed, and displayed correctly.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
		</variablelist>
		<variablelist>
			<title>Insight</title>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1117500">1117500</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Previously, navigating to Cloud -> Instances -> Lifecycle -> Provision Instance and choosing a Ec2 east template returned an error. This was because of a missing provisioning route in VM controller files.

The problem has been fixed in four controller files and the error no longer appears.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1100597">1100597</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>When EVM generated SQL to run a report, it did not qualify a column name with a table name, resulting in an ambigious column reference error.
Hence, EVM was not able to run the report, and returned an incorrectly formed SQL error.
To fix this issue the associations for the fields utilized in the report were corrected so that the table name is correctly inserted in the SQL query.
User is now able to run the report without any failures.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1117972">1117972</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In a RHOSP-4 environment, when issuing a "Refresh Relationships and Power states" to collect instances, images etc, there was an error in the evm log without getting relationship information. This was because the server was using a flavor that is not public. Once access to a flavor has been restricted, no other projects besides the ones granted explicit access will be able to see the flavor, including the admin project.

Code has been updated to fix the issue with private flavors not being visible on refresh.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1144572">1144572</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Amazon region support required overloading the hostname column, but this conflicted with adding support for OpenStack regions where a hostname was also required. A new SQL column for EMS provider_region has been added, and the use of hostname for Amazon regions removed. The region select element in the UI now displays "region" instead of "hostname" for Amazon regions.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1141203">1141203</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Previously, 'Hosts' was erroneously displayed twice in the relationships accordion on the left hand side of the SCVMM screen. Now, one instance of 'Hosts' has been changed to 'Clusters'.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1135606">1135606</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>CFME sent a "suspend" request to put an OpenStack instance into a suspended state, but sent "unpause" to wake it up. This caused the OpenStack instance not to resume from the suspended state. CFME has been updated to send the correct 'resume' request for instances that are suspended. OpenStack instances can now be suspended and resumed as expected.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1120836">1120836</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>New Amazon EC2 instance types were causing an error in the appliance when refreshing an Amazon region with these new types deployed. The list of EC2 instance types has been updated and a region refresh works as expected.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1135069">1135069</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Some Amazon instance types require a specific virtualization type, either 'hvm' or 'paravirtual'. CFME did not account for this, which caused AWS EC2 errors, for example:

AWS::EC2::Errors::InvalidParameterCombination]: Virtualization type 'hvm' is required for instances of type 't2.small' on provisioning cloud instance of type t2.small

CFME now maps from the virtualization_type in the AMI to the virtualization types listed for the instance types, so appropriate instance types are displayed in the UI.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1140698">1140698</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Previously, when Openstack Neutron was configured with the NoOpFirewall handler, attempting to access the security groups returned a 404 error. Since the codebase does not handle non-successful API HTTP return codes, CFME instead attempts to ignore and log any 404 errors.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1138857">1138857</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Previously, SCVMM powershell cmdlets returned a ComputerName value set to "getaddrinfo failed_x000A_" for some Linux VMs. As a result, the VM Hostname property was set to "Unavailable", and the following warning was added to the scvmm.log file: "MIQ(EmsRefresh::Parsers::Scvmm.process_computer_name) Invalid hostname value returned from SCVMM: getaddrinfo failed_x000A_". This was fixed by adding a missing /etc/hosts entry. Now, the hostname shows correctly.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1141208">1141208</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Previously, in the 'Hosts and Clusters' list in the relationship tree, no hosts were displayed, despite hosts existing. This happened when no cluster node had been configured in the SCVMM screen, because no relationship was created between the hosts and the 'host folder'. Now, the property of the 'host folder' is set to clusters when clusters have been configured, and hosts when clusters have not been configured.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1129462">1129462</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>A wrapper for the Ceilometer service was not created when OpenStack wrapper code was added to handle tenant-specific queries. This caused OpenStack Capacity and Utilization data collection to fail on CFME. This has been fixed by allowing non-wrapped OpenStack services to pass through to the underlying service. OpenStack data collection now operates correctly.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1130275">1130275</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>This update fixes an issue where an RHOS4 provider would be unable to be added with no Cinder volumes. This meant that there was a 0 in all data rows in the Relationships section of the provider's detail page and an error message appeared in the evm.log. The Openstack Refresh with no volumes has now been fixed so that if no volumes are present in Cinder the "#process_collection_item" method is never called, and that method creates the entry in the "@data" object in the ems_refresh parser. This means that a provider can be added with successful relationships and no error will appear in the logs.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1141319">1141319</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Tenant fields were not available in the Reporting Engine. The cloud models have been updated to include Cloud Tenants.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1135605">1135605</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>On the summary page, CFME incorrectly labelled suspended OpenStack instance power states temporarily as "suspended" then, after a refresh, as "off". CFME has been updated to use VM raw_power_state. The power state for OpenStack instances now displays correctly in the UI.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1099215">1099215</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>When adding a RHEV provider (3.3) to CFME 5.2.3, the scan did not surpass 100 hosts.

RHEV-M Hosts and StorageDomain Collections are obtained via pagination. This allows CloudForms to inventory larger than default (100) number of hosts and storage domains from RHEV-M.

Changing the default page size (to higher than 100) in the engine is a workaround until the code supports pagination.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1108331">1108331</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Support for custom attributes for services has been added to the new version of CloudForms Management Engine. These attributes may be used for storing meta-data about services. Automation can now use the "custom_keys", "custom_set", and "custom_get" methods to manipulate the custom attributes on a service. Custom services attributes are also visible on the service details page.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
		</variablelist>
<!--		<variablelist>
			<title>Security</title>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1040013">1040013</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>TBA
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
		</variablelist>-->
		<variablelist>
			<title>SmartProxy</title>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1143939">1143939</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Previously, a typo in the assert_privileges call meant that users were experiencing authorization issues when attempting to edit smartproxies. This typo has been corrected and users can now edit smartproxies as expected.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1038378">1038378</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Starting a stopped virtual machine failed due to an error reading XML configuration files. Nokogiri is now used to load XML configuration files and convert them to UTF-8 so Rexml can process them. Starting a stopped virtual machine now completes successfully.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1038394">1038394</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Host refresh did not work on a VM started through the hyperv console as resolution of the hostname was causing inventory collection to fail. The hostname resolution has been fixed, and VMs can now be refreshed.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
		</variablelist>
		<!--<variablelist>
			<title>task</title>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1092895">1092895</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>TBA
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
		</variablelist>-->
		<variablelist>
			<title>To Be Determined</title>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1054866">1054866</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>If an RHSM subscription for OpenShift included the cf-me-5.2-for-rhel-6-rpms channel, its ruby193-rubygem-nokogiri package tried to obsolete OpenShift's ruby-nokogiri package, resulting in dependency issues when installing OpenShift cartridges. An unnecessary Obsoletes entry has been removed, and the packages no longer conflict.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1121162">1121162</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>A missing association when building a report based on Zones caused the following error:  ERROR -- : [ActiveRecord::ConfigurationError]: Association named 'vms_and_templates' was not found; perhaps you misspelled it?  Method:[rescue in _async_generate_table].  The virtual associations for Zones have now been added to Host and VmOrTemplate, and reports based on Zones build as expected.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
		</variablelist>
		<variablelist>
			<title>vulnerability</title>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1077359">1077359</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>It was found that Red Hat CloudForms exposed default routes that were reachable via HTTP(S) requests. An authenticated user could use this flaw to access potentially sensitive controllers and actions that would allow for privilege escalation.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1092894">1092894</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>It was found that Red Hat CloudForms contained an insecure send method that accepted user-supplied arguments. An authenticated user could use this flaw to modify the program flow in a way that could result in privilege escalation.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
		</variablelist>
		<variablelist>
			<title>WebUI</title>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1093178">1093178</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>On template summary screen, the analysis history value is clickable, but upon clicking throwed an error: "Error caught: [NoMethodError] undefined method 'id' for nil:NilClass".

Fixed calls to identify_record to pass in db as VmOrTemplate, default db being used was "self.class.model" which was VmInfra and was incorrect when user is on a template summary screen. This has now fixed the issue and there is no error reported.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1133103">1133103</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the older version of Cloud Forms Management Engine, when a checkbox field was marked as required in the service dialog editor, the required attribute would not persist after exiting from the editor. This was fixed by changing the service dialog editor code to ensure that the required attribute would be saved to the database. Additional fixes were made to ensure that the backend code handled the checkbox state correctly depending on whether the checkbox was clicked or not in the User Interface.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1142875">1142875</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Previously, adding a Control Policy would fail with exception due a flaw in the paging_controls_url method. This has now been removed and two new methods have been added for adding and updating URL query string parameters so that adding a Control Policy works as expected.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1129289">1129289</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>An undefined method error occurred when attempting to assign chargeback rates due to a chargeback rate table being assigned to a tag that had been subsequently deleted. The code has been updated to set current tag assignments to blank when a tag or category has been deleted from the table and rates can be correctly assigned.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1122253">1122253</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>The Smart Management Tag window was missing from the Security Groups Summary page.
Code has been updated and the Smart Management Tag window has been added to the Security Group Summary page and the issue is now resolved.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1101820">1101820</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>The function handling, sorting, and moving of element values did not receive correct parameters from it's caller.
Hence, when a user created a service dialog with an element that sorted the input by "None" and attempted to position element values in a certain order, he got the error "No fields were selected to move 'up'". The user was unable to move element values to the desired position.
A number of changes were made to fix the issues with sorting and moving of drop down list field element values.
The user is now able to position element values as desired.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1123144">1123144</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Navigating to host Drift History caused an unexpected error in the UI.

Code was updated to reset @display when viewing drift history screen to fix an issue where @display was still being set to vms/storages etc after clicking on links to relationships from host summary screen, and then clicking on Drift History link from listnav on left side it was trying to render incorrect partial due to @display being set incorrectly. Drift History link from right side of the summary screen however was working fine because going to summary screen resets @display back to "main".
Additionally added code to set session[:compare_db] to get drift_history link in listnav to send up correct compare_db when it was clicked right after clicking a link to view list of VMS or list of other items through relationships.
The above changes have now fixed the issue and there is no error reported when viewing drift history.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1123195">1123195</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Selecting group by in capacity and utilization of hosts threw an unexpected error: “undefined method 'report_results' for nil:NilClass [host/perf_chart_chooser] displayed in Ui.”

The code that was setting 'interval' local variable has been deleted as it was not being used in the method and was causing a crash when changing a value in "Group By" on Host C&amp;U screen when there is no C&amp;U data available for the chosen group. This has now fixed the issue and there is no error reported.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1122039">1122039</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Previously, an instance could not be terminated by marking it's quadicon and selecting the "Terminate" power option when accessed through a cloud provider. This meant that the "Terminate initiated" message would not display, and the instance was not terminated.

Now, the button methods have been updated to handle the Terminate instance button. As a result, the "Terminate initiated" message displays, and the instance is properly terminated.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1121772">1121772</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Previously, left-clicking a data point on host C&amp;U graphs resulted in an "Action not implemented [host/show]" error.

Now, a route has been added to the chart menu links, and this problem no longer occurs.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1138858">1138858</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>When attempting to provision a VM on SCVMM, user is able to select a template and then receives an error "uninitialized constant MiqProvisionMicrosoftWorkflow [vm_infra/pre_prov]"

Disabled provisioning button for SCVMM. Added code around Publish button to be disabled for SCVMM on VM summary screen and also code around Publish button on list view to display a flash message "Publish does not apply to VM Template" when SCVMM VM is selected from a list view.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1140655">1140655</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the user interface, when navigating to clouds -> providers and selecting a cloud provider, the ActionController returned a routing error. This bug fix adds in the missing icon for routing and the error no longer returns.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1138838">1138838</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Previously, on the cloud tenant provider summary page, after editing relationship options, changes were not reflected. This bug fix adds support for buttons in the cloud tenant controller so changes do take effect.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1132320">1132320</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>This update fixes an issue where "uninitialized constant HostVmwareEsx::SOAP" is displayed as the error for Web Services validation when editing a Host. When going to Infrastructure then Hosts and editing a host to add invalid credentials for Web Services a confusing error message is displayed. The SOAP::Error has been removed from exception filtering since soap4r is no longer used. This means this error message will no longer be displayed.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1091554">1091554</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>A user with VM and Template Access Restrictions other than “None”, when clicks on a particular catalog item that were able to view under Services/Catalogs/Catalog Items, causes the browser to freeze (spinning) forever.

If a user has access restrictions on Catalog Items, to prevent the items from being displayed and accessed, rbac_filtered_objects checks were added around ServiceTemplate nodes in the trees in Catalogs Explorer, and also on the right side of the screen which has fixed the issue.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1126364">1126364</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>A new user assigned the User role received an error message when attempting to provision a cloud instance or vm: "The user is not authorized for this task or item". Access to view the Request list and copy/delete has been added to the User role. In addition, a user will now be redirected back to the page where they initiated a Provisioning request if they don't have access to view the list of Requests to prevent errors in the UI.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1138469">1138469</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>When switching view types between grid, tile, and list views, routing errors returned. This bug fix adds code to retain existing URL parameters across different view types so the routing error no longer returns.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1099484">1099484</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>A code problem caused a "Current_group is not included in the list" error when attempting to create a new user using EvmGroup-user for the group name. The code has been updated to save user.miq_groups instead of user.current_group in controller code when adding/saving a user record.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1138366">1138366</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Downloading a Timelines report in PDF format results in the following error: undefined method 'report' for nil:NilClass [dashboard/render_pdf]. This bug fix updates the application_controller.rb file so reports can now be downloaded in PDF format without errors.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1092716">1092716</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>When an OpenStack instance has multiple security groups assigned, the CloudForms web UI for that instance detail only has reference to one of the security groups the instance is assigned to. The security groups themselves seem to display this relationship accurately in that all VMs that have a security group assigned are seen, but not from the instance detail.

Fixed link to Security Groups to show the list of security groups. Thereby, the CloudForms webUI now displays all the security groups on the instance summary page, so the issue is fixed.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1099389">1099389</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the beta version of CloudForms Management Engine 5.3, the "Starting Time (UTC)" field on the "Add a new schedule page" was covered by the Add and Cancel button bar and was not accessible. This was due to incorrect form layout of the schedule page. This bug was fixed by correcting the formatting errors on the schedule page. The schedule page now displays all the form elements correctly.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1099341">1099341</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In Configuration > Setting > Schedules, unable to create schedule for action "Database Backup", resulting in an error displayed on UI: undefined method 'display_name' for nil:NilClass [ops/schedule_form_field_changed]

Fix implemented to create schedule for action database backup and the issue has now been resolved.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1120096">1120096</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Previously, the web based VMRC console was having issues with different browsers. As a result, the VMRC console button was disabled in Google Chrome, and both Firefox and Internet Explorer were displaying a "Action not implemented" error.

Now, the VMRC connectivity issues have been fixed by adding a missing route, and the VMRC screen launches as expected.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1128873">1128873</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>A typo in the admin role features list code resulted in the evmgroup-administrator role not having access to the Automate Customization page. The typo has been corrected, and the role now has appropriate access.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1103341">1103341</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the previous version of CloudForms Management Engine, the user had to press and hold the mouse button when selecting a listed group to change their role. This made changing roles needlessly difficult. This was due to a bug in the Java script code that handled role selection. It was fixed by correcting the Java script code. The user is now able to select a role without having to press and hold the mouse button.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1128894">1128894</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Reloading requests in Services/Requests threw a rails exception appears: undefined method 'sub_table' for nil:NilClass [miq_request/button]. The rendering issue while reloading a Request has now been fixed. Rendering would be based on @display type - "main" or "miq_provisions". This has now fixed the issue and no error is reported.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1118902">1118902</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>The UI was inaccessible within minutes after adding a RHOS provider to the CFME appliance.

Ensuring the PID file exists within the watchdog_spec.rb and watchdog.rb files means that the UI is now still accessible after adding a RHOS provider.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1117431">1117431</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>On the timelines page, when selecting the daily interval option, the event balloon did not pop up. This bug fix added miq_timeline to the UI css file so the daily interval option works without errors.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1115717">1115717</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Self service users are able to order catalog items only if they clicked "Order" versus clicking on the item and then clicking "Order". This was attributed to the issue where logged in user didn't have access to :sandt_tree.

Fixed code to pass in correct tree name to x_build_node_id method which has fixed the issue and self service users can now order a service without viewing catalog items.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1140648">1140648</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Previously, the SCVMM host icon does not match the provider icon and is incorrect. This bug fix updates the SCVMM host icon to use the standard Microsoft logo so standard corporate logos are used for both RHEV and VMware within Red Hat CloudForms.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1144071">1144071</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Previously, selecting 'Graphical View' for a SmartProxy did nothing due to a routing error. The routing for this has been added and Graphical View for SmartProxies works as expected.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1145296">1145296</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>When adjusting column widths of the displayed table for a list of requests, a routing error returns. This bug fix updates ActionController with save_col_widths so that the routing error no longer returns.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1129495">1129495</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>This update fixes an issue with editing a previously created Catalog Item for VMware using the provision type of PXE due to a missing route. This caused errors when trying to edit a Catalog Item for VMware when using the provision type of PXE. A route has been added for sorting PXE grids. This means that Catalog Items for VMware when using the provision type of PXE can now be edited.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1129802">1129802</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Need to copy Automate class/instance/method elements in the same domain with a new name.

Code was updated to add support to be able to copy a single automate Class/Instance/Method with a new name under same domain. Made model changes to copy methods to call appropriate method when copying objects. Also, added new name text field on copy form that is only displayed when a single object is selected to copy and under a same domain. And, added a read only field "From Domain" to show users which domain they are copying object from.
Changed label "Domain" on Domain pull-down to "to Domain".
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1113062">1113062</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Clicking on download links in Optimize > Utilization results in a blank page. [NoMethodError] undefined method '[]' for nil:NilClass" in production log
This was because the code was only handling enable/disable of download buttons when switching tabs. Buttons were not getting enabled/disabled based upon result data when user sent up tree_select transaction while user was on Reports tab.

Code has been changed to enable/disable Download buttons on Reports tab in Utilization explorer which has fixed the problem.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1111746">1111746</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>When resizing a column width in the list view, an routing error returned. This bug fix adds routing for 'save_col_widths' in the FlavorController and also checked in all other controllers so that this routing error is no longer returned.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1110971">1110971</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Clicking on a service for a catalog item and setting ownership under configuration menu throws an error: undefined method id for nil:NilClass [service/x_button]

Unnecessary code was deleted where @record.id was being passed to locals while setting ownership on a service which has fixed the issue and no error is thrown.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1098998">1098998</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the previous version of CloudForms Management Engine, comparing virtual machines from the data stores summary page resulted in an action not implemented error displayed in the user interface. This bug was due to missing routing information for the compare button. The missing route information was added to the comparison code to fix this bug. It is now possible to compare VMs as expected from the database summary page.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1098497">1098497</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>IE8 LDAP group switching led to 403 forbidden error in Win7/IE8. IE8 403 forbidden errors have now been fixed such as logging in (dried), changing LDAP groups and adding, removing, resetting dashboard widgets. There is no more redirect to 403 forbidden page on group switching, thus the issue has been fixed.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1110964">1110964</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In Infrastructure > Virtual Machines, clicking on timeline after selecting a tempate with timeline enabled threw an undefined method 'first_and_last_event' for nil:NilClass [vm_infra/tl_chooser] because find for VmInfra record was breaking MiqTemplate record.

Added a new method controller_to_model that can be used to pass in model to identify_record call which has fixed the issue and no error is displayed when clicked on template timeline.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1135044">1135044</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>After a copy of a certain built-in CFME Class from the ManageIQ domain into a custom domain, certain characters were replaced with html safe versions causing exceptions during StateMachine running. This was being caused by the haml-4.0.3 gem altering the passed in parameters when escaping the text_field_tag value. Code was updated in a way that escape_once works on frozen strings, that way it works the same way as #html_escape. This has now fixed the issue.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1134053">1134053</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>When provisioning a virtual machine, action changes were not reflected. This bug fix updates vm_infra controller with sort_iso_img_grid so that the routing error no longer returns.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1133708">1133708</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>When making web services calls, it is difficult to locate GUIDs because they were not present on the Service Summary page. This bug fix updates the textual_summary.rb file so that GUIDs are presented on the Service Summary page.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1110244">1110244</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>When the user navigated to Cloud Intelligence -> Reports -> Import/Export then clicked on the Export button without first selecting a report to view, they received an error. This was because the Export button was available to the user before they chose a report.

Now, the export button is disabled and unavailable to the user, but becomes available once they select a report from the "Available Reports" list.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1131566">1131566</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>This update fixes an issue where clicking on nodes in the VM Genealogy Tree causes a routing error. Routes have now been added to allow clicking on nodes in the VM Genealogy Tree. This means that the information for the node in the VM Genealogy Tree can now be viewed.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1098112">1098112</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the beta version of Cloud Forms Management Engine 5.3, it was not possible to modify the paginator value when listing virtual machines through their relationships with other objects. This was because the paginator did not handle list value updates in these views. This bug was fixed by enabling the handler for per-page setting and sorting of records in relationship views. The paginator now works as expected in relationship views.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1133660">1133660</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Previously, when users tried to navigate to the EVM group under CloudIntelligence/Reports/EditReportMenus/AllEvmGroups/, an undefined local variable or method 'nodeid' error returned. This bug fix updates the report_controller.rb file and the navigation can now be made successfully.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1146265">1146265</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the beta version of CloudForms Management Engine UI, when users clicked on Amazon instances under Cloud -> Instances, they got an undefined method error message. This issue was fixed by fixing the link to a 'Cloud Tenant' from the instance summary screen. Additionally, a check was added to fix undefined_method 'cloud_tenant ' error for an Amazon instance. In the latest version users can successfully view Amazon instance summary screen.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1131696">1131696</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the older version of Cloud Forms Management Engine, when using Selected Infrastructure Providers as assignment, clicking the save button reset the assignment user interface leading the customer to believe that the rates have not been assigned. This issue is fixed in the latest version. Now the values are assigned correctly.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1097692">1097692</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the beta version of CloudForms Management Engine 5.3, if the administrator attempted to create a catalog under the services menu, it resulted in a fatal error stating that the user was not authorized for the task. This was because the role based access control rule to permit the administrator to create the catalog was missing. This bug was fixed by adding the missing role based access control rule. The administrator is now able to create catalogs as expected.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1094451">1094451</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the beta version of CloudForms Management Engine 5.3, adding a Red Hat Open Stack provider failed with an undefined method error message. This error was a result of incorrect handling of the value provided for the port number field. This bug was fixed by correcting the code to handle the port number value correctly. The user is now able to add a Red Hat OpenStack provider as expected.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1147081">1147081</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the beta version of CloudForms Management Engine 5.3, if a user had restricted access to Automate and its sub menu options using role based access control, the user would get a blank page when accessing the Simulation sub menu. Additionally, an error was logged to the production log that the user was not authorized for the task or item. This error was due to an incorrect parameter being passed to the method used to assert priveleges. This bug was fixed by passing in the correct parameter ot the assert priveleges method. The restricted access user is now able to access the simulation sub menu as expected.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1094511">1094511</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In Customization, adding a new dialog with dynamic drop down list field, and in Service > Catalogs, adding a generic service and order, threw the following error after refresh.

Dynamic dropdown list error: undefined method ‘refresh_button_pressed’ for &lt;DialogFieldTextBox:0x0000000a830428&gt; [catalog/dynamic_list_refresh]

Code has been updated and the problem is now fixed.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1132556">1132556</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Editing an existing service catalog item returns the following error: Action not implemented [catalog/x_button]. This bug fix updates the miq_request_workflow.rb file so service catalog items can be edited as normal.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1138837">1138837</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Previously, when adding a new domain, the UI displays 'Adding a new Automate Namespace' and was incorrect. This bug fix updates the UI with the correct text and now displays 'Adding a new Automate Domain'.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1095830">1095830</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the beta version of CloudForms Management Engine 5.3, when examining a virtual machine's properties, the accordion containing the virtual machine name was incorrectly formatted and looked like a tab. This bug was fixed by correcting the formatting of the accordion class. The virtual machine name accordion is now formatted correctly.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1132331">1132331</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>When editing registration details and entering Red Hat account information, the following error returned: Credential validation returned: stack level too deep. This bug fix removes the mixing enumerable into string so that successful validation is returned.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1108320">1108320</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>There was a naming mismatch for the product option Settings and Operation. Label changed from "Settings and Operations" to "Configure" to match the UI tab and the issue has been fixed.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1096388">1096388</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In Automate -> Customization -> Provisioning Dialogs accordion, attempting to sort a folder selection that contains provisioning dialogs by name or description does not work and results in a 500 error in log.

Fixed DoubleRender error when user try to sort list of provisioning dialogs, which has now resolved the issue.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1132042">1132042</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the older version of Cloud Forms Management Engine, an incomplete icon is displayed when connecting to a newly added RHEVM provider. This was fixed by adding the missing connecting state icons. The correct connecting state icon is displayed now.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1146236">1146236</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>When selecting 'Performance - VMs'  in the 'Base the report on' field,  tag fields were not available. This bug fix updates the WebUI and includes tag fields for virtual machines.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1133052">1133052</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the older version of Cloud Forms Management Engine, service tags were not available to be selected as fields to be included in service reports. This was fixed by adding the service tags to the tag class. Service tag fields are now available in service reports.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1097876">1097876</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the beta version of CloudForms Management Engine 5.3, when running a simulation under Automate, the type pull down field would use a value from the earlier run if "None" was selected for the current run, resulting in an undefined method error. This was fixed by correcting the code to reset the target id when "None" was selected in the Type pull down field. The simulation now runs as expected without any errors.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1145840">1145840</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>A new feature Cloud tenant was added in the Instance view Relationship in CloudForms Management Engine. This was done because, in the beta version of CFME, when a user selected an instance from Cloud/Instances and scrolled down to the relationships section of the insight data, he found that the selected tenant relationship was missing.
This new feature enables users to be able to view an instance and understand which tenant it is provisioned into.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1094300">1094300</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the beta version of CloudForms Management Engine 5.3, the reports accordion showed the null string when a report was queued to be run, and a No Class found error was reported for the explorer tree node. This error was a result of adding the Generating Report tree node with the wrong options. This bug was fixed by providing the correct options when adding the Generating Report tree node. The generating report message is now displayed correctly when a report is queued to be run.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1110171">1110171</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>When adding multiple dashboards, the first one of them is not displayed in the selector on dashboard. Creating only one dashboard, selector is not displayed, but logout/login was the only option to fix the problem.

In DashboardController: Added condition to display all new dashboards which has now fixed the problem.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1098203">1098203</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the beta version of CloudForms Management Engine 5.3, all links under the datastore content accordion contained the text "Datastore None" instead of text describing the link. This bug was fixed by correcting the link text when the link was both active and inactive. The UI now shows the correct link text under the datastore content accordion.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1110544">1110544</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In Infrastructure PXE, adding a new customization template failed to save the template text, although the template is saved.

Updated code which has now fixed the problem.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1112574">1112574</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Clicking on the Intelligence/Reports button after deleting the last of the reports caused the contents of the page to disappear, except for the top menu, due to a problem with the page rendering.

The error was fixed by setting the active node to be "root" whenever a non-existent custom report node was made as a result of deleting a custom report. The page now renders as expected.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1098429">1098429</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the beta version of CloudForms Management Engine 5.3, clicking on the Navigation links in the Cloud Intelligence Reports menu item resulted in a no route matches fatal error for the progress indicator image in the production log. This was due to missing information for the progress indicator image. The error was fixed by adding the missing information for the progress indicator. With the fix, the error is no longer seen in the log.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1093735">1093735</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the beta version of CloudForms Management Engine 5.3, attempting to create a virtual machine snapshot without providing a name for the snapshot resulted in an undefined local variable or method error. This was because the form input was not validated by the web user interface. This bug was fixed by validating input in the web user interface. The web user interface now gracefully handles invalid input when creating snapshots.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1113077">1113077</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In Infrastructure > Requests, unchecking all the approval states and clicking on reload resulted in an undefined method 'keys' for nil:NilClass [miq_request/button] in the UI.

Fixed reload button on request page and an appropriate flash message is displayed.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1130664">1130664</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>This update fixes an issue where the Show Cloud Provider Quadrants is not checked by default in Settings. Show Infrastructure Provider Quadrants is already checked by default and Show Cloud Provider Quadrants should also be checked by default. A default setting was added for Cloud Provider Quadrants. This means that Cloud Provider Quadrants will now be checked by default.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1113462">1113462</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>On the RHEV platform, when a workload was rebooting, the UI showed a blank power-state icon for the workload.

The image was restored, and the correct image is now displayed during a reboot.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1144540">1144540</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Users restricted only to Automate->Explorer visibility were receiving an "Authentication Failed" message and could not see the "Automate->Explorer" page.

The b/vmdb/db/fixtures/miq_shortcuts.yml file has been updated with a new entry that allows users with Automate->Explorer visibility to see the page upon logging in.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1130251">1130251</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>There was an undefined method 'to_sym' for nil:NilClass [vm/show_list] error during cross hair operations on C&amp;U graphs.

Code was updated to include new paging_controls_url helper to handle extra URL parameters. This has fixed the issue and there is no error reported.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1130250">1130250</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>There was an error when attempting to change the items/page value on the VM list view: undefined method '[]' for nil:NilClass [host/show_list]

Added VM/show_list post route for VM list paging controls. This has fixed the issue and now there is no error reported.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1141375">1141375</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Previously, when a user clicked on 'Snapshots' in the properties section for a virtual machine in the SCVMM screen, the option to add another snapshot was disabled. The correct behavior is that all snapshot functionality should appear as disabled, as snapshot creation is not yet supported for SCVMM virtual machines. As such, all of the snapshot manipulation buttons have now been disabled for SCVMM virtual machines.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1128934">1128934</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>This update fixes an issue with not specifying a type when adding a storage manager. This meant that the storage manager had a rails exception when an appliance was setup for a storage manager without specifying a type. The storage manager type was changed so a blank value could be checked. This means that a storage manager can now be added without a type.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1128923">1128923</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>The 'Save' button in the 'Adding a new Customization Template' has been replaced by the 'Add' button.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1114744">1114744</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In Automate -> Customization -> Provisioning Dialogs accordion, selecting a folder that contains provisioning dialogs, sorting by name or description results in the dialogs being sorted, but the UI footer bar always displays "Sorted by Name".


Updated table footer in the Provisioning Dialog screen: Table footer 'Sort by' is updated when the user wants to sort a table column which has now fixed the problem.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1062382">1062382</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Previously, the Request Table column names don't match up with the Request Detail page. This bug fix updates the _request.html.erb file so that all fields match up.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1136445">1136445</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Previously, when a user selected a service in the 'My Service' window, an 'undefined method' error was returned. This happened in cases where the back end was determining whether to hide the 'Reconfigure' button for services created through automation without an associated service template. Also, the 'Service' dialog lists and radio buttons showed keys instead of human-readable values. Now, these issues have been corrected.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1099136">1099136</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the previous version of CloudForms Management Engine, editing tags for a virtual machine or template under the Services -> Workload menu item resulted in an error that the user was not authorized for the task. This bug occured in the function that asserted user privileges, as the correct product feature id was not passed to the function. This bug was fixed by adding a method to pass the correct product feature id to the function that asserted privileges. Users are now able to edit tags as expected.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1127093">1127093</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Previously, attempting to create a user without defining a group returned an 'unexpected exception' error. Now, the same action returns the following explanatory error: "A User must be assigned to a Group".
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1106335">1106335</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the beta version of CloudForms Management Engine 5.3, the Configure -> About screen did not detect Google Chrome browsers correctly. This was due to missing browser version information in the code that detected the browser. This bug was fixed by adding in the missing browser version information. The About screen now detects Google Chrome browsers correctly.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1127009">1127009</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Previously, the 'Utilization' button on the 'Instances' page was enabled for cloud instances even when no Capacity and Utilization data was available. This caused the 'Instances' page to display a loading icon indefinitely. Now, the 'Utilization' button is disabled for an instance if C&amp;U data is not collected.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1138378">1138378</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Previously, clicking on 'Services' in the upper menu from the 'Infrastructure/Requests' page directed users back to the 'Infrastructure/Requests' page, rather than the 'Services' page. Now the two types of URL are handled separately, and the user is no longer redirected to the incorrect page.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1138392">1138392</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Previously, there was an error in the color setting for reporting. As a result, the Yellow Background option in the Styling tab did not work correctly; a yellow background did not appear in the preview or in the report. To fix this, the "background-image: none;" parameter was removed from the color setting code. Now, a yellow background will successfully appear in reports when selected.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1138396">1138396</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Previously, the main pane and the menu pane had different code for their icon images. This caused the paused and running icons to appear differently in each pane. To fix this, the code was updated to set the same images in both panes. Now all icons are identical in each pane.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1138397">1138397</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Previously, when creating a Catalog Item, after entering Name/Description, Catalog, Dialog, Provisioning Entry Point and clicking Save, the user interface returned an unexpected error. This happened in cases where no virtual machine template was found. Now, a check has been added for the existence of the request object, and a more meaningful error message is displayed when a template is missing.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1138398">1138398</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Previously, navigating to the 'OS information', 'VMM information' and 'Devices' pages in the properties section for a host showed users a hand pointer, which erroneously suggested that those pages contain interactive links. Now, a 'no-hover' class has been added to these pages, and the correct pointer type displays.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1138427">1138427</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Previously, a routing issue caused attempts to edit the tags of a repository to produce the following error: "Action not implemented [repository/button]". Now, the missing route has been added, and tags can be successfully edited.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1126386">1126386</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>This update fixes an issue where a hand pointer appeared on orphaned data pages when there were no clickable links. A no-hover class has been added to the records table so that the hand pointer no longer appears when there are no clickable links.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1126363">1126363</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Logging in as a new user with assigned user role, in Cloud Intelligence > Reports, attempting to download the report(csv/txt or pdf) format results in an error being displayed on the UI: The user is not authorized for this task or item.

Moved hidden features for Report download buttons under View section. If a user can view a report they should be able to download a report. Hidden report download features were under Modify section, if user didn't have access to modify/add reports they were getting User not authorized for this task message when trying to download a report. Also, fixed a typo in feature name text.
The issue has now been resolved.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1099808">1099808</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the beta version of CloudForms Management Engine 5.3, the button to add a new customization template under the PXE main menu item was called "Save" instead of "Add". This bug was fixed by displaying the correct set of buttons while adding a new customization template. The correct buttons are now seen when adding a new PXE customization template.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1143342">1143342</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>The 'Assign Button' label in the Catalogs window has been replaced by the 'Assign Items' label.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1100355">1100355</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>The selection box does not expand correctly and is too small to see what's going on without scrolling from left to right for each selection.

The selection box formatting has been fixed and it now possible to see the selection properly without scrollbars.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1124609">1124609</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In Optimize > Utilization, selecting any cluster or host under any infra provider or selecting any datastore, on the Utilization trend summary page > Details tab, C&amp;U graphs for Cluster, Host and Datastores overlap with the following message: * Information shown is based on available trend data from xx/yy/14 to xx/yz/14 in the UTC time zone.

Replaced chart fieldsets with divs; also added HRs where needed and the issue has now been resolved.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1138859">1138859</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>The class inherit field is not being used currently and should be removed from the UI screen

Removed Inherits from field from Add/Edit class screen.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1091059">1091059</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>When selecting to register a CFME appliance to a satellite server the default channel provided is incorrect. Channel provided is cf-me-5.2-for-rhel-6-rpms which is the default channel name for RHSM. When customers create a satellite server certificate the default name provided by Red Hat is rhel-x86_64-server-6-cf-me-3.

Fixed enablement of Save/Reset button on RHN Updates tab.
Changed haml view to pass in id on default buttons and some of the fields that were missing that. id is used to load @edit from session using load_edit method. Also, changed edit_rhn method to save initial data in @edit[:current] so it can be used to determine whether to enable/disable save/reset buttons on screen. And, code was removed from "reset_repo_name_from_default" method that was setting values directly into session[:edit] hash; changed it to return the default repo name. This has fixed the issue and the default channel for satellite is now correct.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1118400">1118400</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>When navigating to Intelligence -> Chargebacks ->  Assignments and selecting Storage or Compute the left-hand accordion menu becomes grey so it cannot be clicked. Clicking on any other accordion menu did not make them accessible. Also, clicking on the save button did not make the menu accessible.

As there is no cancel button on the Assignments accordion, there was no need to lock this screen. So the lock was removed. The menu is no longer grey, and other menus are accessible.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1142257">1142257</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Previously, Capacity and Utilization tables included an incorrect fieldset that presented a non-interactive element with all the visual appearances of an interactive element. Now, the erroneous fieldset has been removed from these tables and the elements are no longer misrepresented to users.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1104338">1104338</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>CFME UI failed to validate LDAP configuration when the bind password provided contained special characters, without any success or failure indication.

Code fixed to allow longer bind password for LDAP which has now resolved the issue.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1101250">1101250</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the previous version of CloudForms Management Engine, editing an existing report under the Intelligence menu was not possible as the Save button was disabled. This was due to missing functionality in the Java script code used in the edit report screen. This bug was fixed by adding the missing functionality. Reports can now be edited correctly as expected.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1101852">1101852</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the beta version of CloudForms Management Engine 5.3, clicking on the refresh button in the configuration diagnostic page resulted in an error stating that the user was not authorized for the task or item. This was due to a missing product feature property for the refresh button. This issue was fixed by adding the hidden product feature property for the refresh button. The refresh button for the diagnostic page now works as expected.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1121257">1121257</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Previously, the "Container" page for instances and VMs was incorrectly displaying the hand pointer, even though the page had no clickable links. Now, this problem is fixed. As a result, the hand pointer has been removed.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1103105">1103105</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the previous version of CloudForms Management Engine, the  accordion selector in the "Compare VM or Template" page had improper and overlapping dynatree alignment. This was because the comparison sections drift screen did not use a fixed width. This bug was fixed by correcting the comparison sections drift screen to use a fixed width. The accordion selector on the "Compare VM or Template" page now has the correct alignment.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1141180">1141180</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Previously, it was not possible to see in the user interface which snapshots were active for a virtual machine. Now the 'current' property of the snapshot is correctly set, and active snapshots are identified in the UI.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1121249">1121249</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Previously, there were multiple pages that were incorrectly displaying the arrow pointer instead of a hand pointer. Now, after aligning hash rockets and adjusting formatting, this problem is fixed. As a result, the correct cursor hand pointer now displays, along with alternating row colors in List View.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1102590">1102590</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the beta version of CloudForms Management Engine 5.3, the checkbox to select a policy profile for a Virtual Machine on the VM policy assignment page was missing. This was due to an error in the cascading style sheet for the VM policy assignment page. This bug was fixed by correcting the cascading style sheet error. The checkboxes for selecting a VM policy assignment are now displayed correctly.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1141812">1141812</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In Automate > Explorer, and on the accordion, in Infrastructure > VM > Provisioning > Placement class, in an attempt to click on properties and schema page, both pages have hand pointer with no clickable links.

Added missing no-hover class to schema and properties pages. Also, aligned hash rockets, adjusted formatting. With these changes, the problem has now been fixed.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1119487">1119487</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In Infrastructure > Virtual Machines, editing a VM or a Cloud instance threw an unexpected error.

Fixed the breadcrumb link when navigating back to the VM Summary page. This has solved the issue and now there is no unexpected error encountered.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1141353">1141353</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Previously, when viewing the list of images on a RHEL OpenStack Platform provider, it was not possible to perform multiple scans at once. Instead, users had to initiate one scan at a time. Now, a new button has been added to the 'Images' toolbar to scan multiple images.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1129469">1129469</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In Storage Managers > Add New Storage Manager, the Validate button kept switching its position coordinates as fields were entered/deleted on the form. Changed validate button alignment which has now fixed the issue.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1095854">1095854</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the previous version of CloudForms Management Engine, while adding or editing a provider, the Validate button unexpectedly became bold and grew in size after the form was completed. This user interface issue was fixed by ensuring that the Validate button did not grow in size in the new version of CloudForms Management Engine.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1114706">1114706</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Incorrect hover text is shown for 'Datastores' in the Relationships section on VM summary page when in fact it should be "Show this VM's Datastores"

Code has been updated to show the correct hover text and the problem has now been fixed.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1098189">1098189</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the beta version of CloudForms Management Engine 5.3, when the browser interface was loaded in Internet Explorer 8, the background image at the bottom of the page did not cover the entire page width at some screen resolutions. This bug was fixed by adding a new background image having the correct dimensions. The background image now covers the entire page width at all screen resolutions.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1101222">1101222</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the previous version of CloudForms Management Engine, when exporting reports under the intelligence main menu item, if the user clicked on the Export button without selecting any reports, the appliance exported the list of reports that were exported in a previous export. This bug was fixed by disabling the export button until a report was selected. Exporting reports now works as expected.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1116704">1116704</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>From Cloud Intelligence > Reports > Import/Export, uploading an empty yaml file threw an error: undefined method 'collect' for false:FalseClass displayed in UI.

A flash error message has been added when an empty yaml is being imported which has fixed the issue.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1114760">1114760</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Unexpected error was encountered while downloading resource pool report.
Error text "undefined method 'paged_view_search' for nil:NilClass [ems_cluster/download_data]"

Fixed the resource pool report download issue as the session[:view] value is to be stored in the instance variable - @view. This has now fixed the problem and there is no error reported.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1123494">1123494</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>When accessing the Web UI of a CloudForms 5.2.4 with Internet Explorer 8.0.6001.18702, resulted in "403 Permission Denied" errors when clicking on some buttons. This happened even though when logged in to the Web UI, being able to access other pages in it. This behavior was observed while on the grid view of the following pages under "Infrastructure" and clicking the Tile View button.
- Providers
- Resource Pools
- Repositories
The error was also reported when switching from the List View to Grid View.

A whitelist has been created of all known 403 Forbidden errors occurring in IE8 that are caused by IE8 not passing the referer on redirects. The issue has now been resolved.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1108087">1108087</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the beta version of CloudForms Management Engine 5.3, editing the log collection diagnostic configuration settings resulted in a no route matches error. This bug was caused by missing route information for the Type select box. This bug was fixed by adding in the missing route configuration for the Type select box. The user is now able to configure the log type as expected.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1124936">1124936</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>When the user received emailed reports the body of the email was showing <![CDATA[<br/><br/>]]>. This was being set in app/models/miq_report/notification.rb

Code was updated to remove the html tags <![CDATA[<br/>]]> that show up in the emailed report and the problem is now fixed.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1131638">1131638</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the previous version of CloudForms Management Engine user interface, the tab Report Selection had 2 drop downs in one row. This has been fixed in the latest user interface. Now the drop downs appear in different rows.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1133051">1133051</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the older version of Cloud Forms Management Engine, a missing route error about download data was encountered when attempting to download a text or CSV file from the Download drop down menu option under the Flavors option of the Clouds main menu item. This was fixed by adding the missing route information to the VMDB configuration. Downloading flavors data now works as expected.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1134068">1134068</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In Infra > Repositories, selecting the checkbox next to a repository, and clicking Policy > Manage Policies in the toolbar resulted in a missing route error, preventing the page from loading correctly.

Added missing policy protect routes for the Repository controller and the issue has now been resolved.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1147075">1147075</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the beta version of CloudForms Management Engine 5.3, when adding an Amazon EC2 provider, the validate button remained disabled even after all the information required to add the provider was entered. This was because the code to enable the button checked the contents of a non existing text field. This bug was fixed by changing the code to check for content in the correct field. The validate button now gets enabled as expected when adding an Amazon EC2 provider.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1093222">1093222</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Navigating and viewing C&amp;U graphs in RHEV and Openstack required at times greater than 10-15 seconds.
Changed server monitor_poll default to 5 seconds which fixed a number of timing issues which were queue timing delays. C&amp;U especially gets a lot snappier and the effect on the appliance CPU usage was found to be negligible.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1093663">1093663</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the beta version of CloudForms Management Engine 5.3, clicking on any button under Infrastructure -> Virtual Machines resulted in an undefined method error in the production log file. However there was no impact at the user interface level. This bug was fixed by code changes in the appliance back end. These undefined errors are no longer seen in the appliance's production log.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1093389">1093389</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>In the previous version of CloudForms Management Engine, using VMWare's VMRC plugin to access virtual machine consoles failed. This was fixed by enabling the VMRC plugin for Firefox and Chrome browsers. Additional SELinux policy changes may be required to allow the VMRC plugin to run correctly. Users are now able to access virtual machines using the VMRC plugin.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
		</variablelist>
		<variablelist>
			<title>Documentation</title>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1083340">1083340</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>The Integration Guide has been updated with content for the new REST API.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1098238">1098238</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>There were suggestions to add clarity to the section “Customization Templates for Virtual Machine and Instance Provisioning” about ISO provisioning.

Added more information to the section in the CFME Lifecycle and Automation Guide as per suggestions.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1050438">1050438</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>There was a request for Automation Guide to provide more detail on how Error/Retries work.

Added more information in the Automation Guide about on entry and on error, while pointing out how the retry logic, on_entry and on_error are distinct cases in the program flow.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1136943">1136943</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>Previously, after a manual yum update of the 'cfme' and 'cfme-appliance' packages, the appliance would shut down and update, but then fail to start back up again. This was because the $posttrans scriptlet of the CFME RPM contains and executes the following: "posix.exec('/sbin/service', 'evmserverd', 'watchdog_start')". But "evmserverd" doesnt support "watchdog_start" in 5.3, only "start". To get around this, a workaround was documented in the following article: https://access.redhat.com/articles/1198123. Now, by following these steps, the appliance is successfully shut down, updated, and brought back up automatically.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1118505">1118505</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>The CFME Lifecycle and Automation Guide now documents that CFME currently supports the provisioning of VMware ESX hosts and hypervisors only.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1128919">1128919</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>CloudForms documentation directed users to raise bugs against the guides using Bugzilla, but bugs cannot be filed against CloudForms by external users. The feedback section of the guides now instructs users to raise issues through GSS.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1108189">1108189</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>A "Red Hat CloudForms Management Engine NetApp Storage Integration" guide has been created to document the tech preview NetApp provisioning option.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1029520">1029520</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>For EVMProvisionRequestEX, need more information about the supported fields for "vmFields", "Requester" or the other array elements.

Tables have been added for supported fields "EVMProvisionRequestEx" in the CFME Integration Services Guide.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1014500">1014500</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>CloudForms bugs are now publicly visible, but external bugs must be raised through GSS.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1083339">1083339</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>A new User Guide is now available for no-administrative users of CloudForms.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1103043">1103043</ulink></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
<screen>The Installation Guide has been replaced with three platform-specific installation guides: Installing CloudForms on Red Hat Enterprise Virtualization, Installing CloudForms on Red Hat OpenStack Platform, and Installing CloudForms on VMware vSphere.
</screen>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
		</variablelist>
</section>